<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Free Ola Bini!</title>
  <subtitle>Campaign to Free Ola Bini</subtitle>
  <link href="https://freeolabini.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://freeolabini.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-05-03T22:48:53.409+02:00</updated>
  <id>https://freeolabini.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Free Ola Bini</name>
    <email>olabinilegal@riseup.net</email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini ist politischer Gefangener in Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/de/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/de/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aktivisten für freie Software und Privatsphäre dürfen nicht kriminalisiert werden!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privatsphäre ist nichts illegales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/olabini&quot;&gt;@olabini&lt;/a&gt;, ein weltweit bekannter Aktivist im Bereich der freien Software und engagierter Verteidiger von Grundrechten und Privatsphäre wurde am 11. April 2019 um 15:20h am Flughaften in Quito, Ecuador verhaftet.
Soweit wir wissen, gibt es keine Anklage gegen ihn.
Ihm wurde nicht erlaubt mit seinen Anwälten zu sprechen, obwohl er bereits über 17 Stunden festgehalten wurde.
Um 18:00h wurde seinen Anwälten gesagt, er würde zum Verhör ins Büro des Staatsanwalts im nördlichen Quito gebracht.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini ist ein schwedischer Staatsbürger, der in Equador lebt und kein fließendes Spanisch spricht.
Er würde einen Übersetzer für seine Befragung benötigen.
Seine Festnahme ist illegal, da ihm nicht gesagt wird, was ihm vorgeworfen wird und sein Heimatland (Schweden) entgegen internationaler Gepflogenheiten nicht über seine Festnahme informiert wurde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Er ist Technischer Leiter des &lt;em&gt;Center for Digital Autonomy&lt;/em&gt; und hat auf seinem Twitter-Account angekündigt, dass er für einen Kampfsportkurs nach Japan reisen wollte.
Diese Reise war bereits seit Monaten geplant.
Vor seiner Festnahme kommentierte er die Aussagen von Ecuadors Innenminister auf Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/olabini/status/1116341908371062794&quot;&gt;“María Paula Romo, Ecuardors Innenminister, hat heute morgen in einer Pressekonferenz  behauptet, dass russische Hacker in Ecuador leben und dass ein Mitglied von Wikileaks seit Jahren in Ecuador lebt.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini ist bereits sein ganzes Leben Softwareentwickler und hat mit 8 Jahren als Kind angefangen zu programmieren.
Er hat selbst zwei Programmiersprachen geschaffen und ist ein langjähriger Aktivist für freie Software und Transparenz.
Die 2010er Ausgabe der Schwedischen Computerworld hat Bini als Top 6 der wichtigsten Entwickler des Landes geführt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Er hat an folgenden Projekten mitgewirkt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini arrested in Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/en/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/en/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;People working for free software and privacy should not be criminalized&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing criminal about wanting privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, @olabini, a world-renowned figure in the field of free software and defender of digital rights and privacy, was arrested at the airport in Quito, Ecuador at 3:20 p.m. local time on April 11, 2019. As far as is known, there are no charges against him. His lawyers were not allowed to meet him all day yesterday and only gained access to him after he was detained for 17 hours. At 6 p.m. they were told that they were going to transfer him to the Flagrante Delicto Unit (Unidad de Flagrancia de la Fiscalía) of the Attorney General’s office in central northern Quito to give statements in an investigation by the provincial Attorney General’s office in Pichincha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini, a Swedish citizen living in Ecuador, does not speak fluent Spanish and requires an interpreter to make any statement. He has been held illegally, without known charges and without informing the authorities of his country (Sweden) of his detention as established by international protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is the Technical Director of Center for Digital Autonomy and had posted on his twitter account that he was going to travel to Japan for a martial arts course, a trip planned more than a month ago. He saw comments from Ecuador’s Minister of Interior, and tweeted: “María Paula Romo, Ecuador Minister of the Interior, this morning held a press conference, claiming there are Russian hackers in Ecuador, and also that there is one person part of WikiLeaks living in Ecuador since several years.” (https://twitter.com/olabini/status/1116341908371062794)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini has been a software programmer his entire life, having started programming as an 8 year old child, and created two programming languages. He’s a long time Free Software and privacy and transparency activist. In 2010 Computerworld from Sweden, rated Ola Bini as the 6th top developer in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has contributed to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini arestita en Ekvadoro</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/eo/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/eo/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Homoj kiuj laboras por la libera programaro kaj la privateco ne devas esti trakitaj kiel kriminuloj.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voli privatecon estas neniel krima.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, @olabini, monda renoma indulo en la fako de la libera programaro kaj defendanto de la ciferaj rajtoj kaj privateco, estis arestita en la flughaveno en Kito, Ekvadoro je la 3:20 ptm. loka horo en la 11a Aprilo de 2019. Kiel estas konita, ne estas akuzoj kontraŭ ri. Riaj advokantoj ne estis lasita kunveni kun ri dum la tuta tago hieraŭ kaj nur akiris alireblo al ri post ri estis 17 horoj detenita. Je la 6 ptm. al ili oni diris, ke ili transirigus rin al la ŝtata institucio pri krima esplorado (hispane &lt;em&gt;Unidad de Flagrancia de la Fiscalía&lt;/em&gt;) en la centrala oficejo en la meza-norda Kito por deklari en enketo de la provinca krima oficejo en Pichincha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini, sveda civitano loĝanta en Ekvadoro, ne flue parolas la hispanan
kaj bezonas interpretanton por deklari ion. Ri estis detenita malleĝe
sen konataj akuzaĵoj kaj sen informi la aŭtoritatojn el ria lando (Svedo) pri ria detento kiel internaciaj protokoloj konstatas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ri estas la Teĥnika Direktoro de la Ejo por Cifera Aŭtonomeco (hispane &lt;em&gt;Centro de Autonomía Digital&lt;/em&gt;) kaj afiŝis en sia konto de Twitter, ke ri iros al Japano al luktosporta kurso, vojaĝo planita pli ol unu monato antaŭe. Ri vidis komentojn de la Ministro pri Internaj Aferoj, kaj pepis: «María Paula Romo, ekvadora Ministro pri Internaj Aferoj, gazetare konferencis dirinte, ke estas rusaj kodumuloj en Ekvadoro, kaj ankaŭ, ke estas homo el WikiLeaks loĝante en Ekvadoro ekde kelkaj jaroj en Ekvadoro, kaj ankaŭ, ke estas homo el WikiLeaks loĝante en Ekvadoro ekde kelkaj jaroj» (https://twitter.com/olabini/status/1116341908371062794).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini estis programisto sian tutan vivon, komencinte programi kiel 8-jara infano, kaj kreis du programlingvojn. Ri estis longatempe aktivulo pri libera programaro kaj privateco kaj malkaŝeca aktivulo. En 2010 Computerworld el Svedo, taksis Ola Bini kiel la 6a pli bona programisto de la lando.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ri kontribuis al:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini arrestado en Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/es/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/es/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;La gente que trabaja en software libre y la privacidad no debe ser criminalizada&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No hay nada criminal en querer privacidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, @olabini, una reconocida figura en el ámbito de software libre mundial y defensor de los derechos digitales y la privacidad en Internet, fue detenido en el aeropuerto de Quito, Ecuador a las 15h20 del 11 de abril de 2019. Hasta donde se sabe, no hay cargos ni pruebas en su contra. No se le permitió a sus abogados reunirse con él todo el día de ayer. A las 18h00 se les dijo que lo iban a trasladar a la Unidad de Flagrancia de la Fiscalía en el centro norte de Quito para rendir declaraciones en el marco de una investigación de la Fiscalía provincial de Pichincha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini, ciudadano sueco residente en Ecuador no habla fluentemente el español y requiere de un intérprete para rendir cualquier declaración. Se le ha retenido ilegalmente, sin cargos conocidos, sin comunicar a las autoridades de su país (Suecia) su detención como establecen los protocolos internacionales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini es el Director Técnico del Centro de Autonomía Digital y habría posteado en su cuenta de twitter que iba a viajar a Japón para un curso de artes marciales, un viaje planeado hace más de un mes. Vio los comentarios de la ministra del Interior y tweeteo: “María Paula Romo, la Ministra del Interior del Ecuador, esta mañana mantuvo una rueda de prensa, donde se alegaba que hackers rusos viven en Ecuador, y que una persona cercana a Wikileaks vive ahí también”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini ha sido un programador de software toda su vida. Comenzó a programar desde los 8 años y creó dos lenguajes de programación. Ha sido un activista de privacidad y software libre por mucho tiempo. En el 2010, Computerworld en Suecia, lo nombró como el 6to mejor desarrollador del país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha contribuido con:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini arrêté en Equateur</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/fr/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/fr/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Les personnes qui travaillent dans le logiciel libre et la défense de la vie privée ne doivent pas être criminalisées&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il n&#39;y a rien de criminel à vouloir protéger la vie privée..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, @olabini, personnalité renommée dans le domaine du logiciel libre mondial et défenseur des droits numériques et de la vie privée sur Internet, a été interpellé à l&#39;aéroport de Quito, en Équateur, à 15h20 le 11 avril 2019. Il n&#39;y a pas d&#39;accusation ou preuves contre lui. Ses avocats n&#39;ont pas été autorisés à le rencontrer toute la journée le jour de son arrestation. À 18h00, ils ont été informés qu&#39;ils allaient le transférer à l&#39;Unité des Flagrances au centre-nord de Quito pour qu&#39;il fasse des déclarations dans le cadre d&#39;une enquête menée par le Bureau du Procureur de la Province de Pichincha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini, citoyen suédois résidant en Équateur, ne parle pas couramment l&#39;espagnol et a besoin d&#39;un interprète pour faire une déclaration. Il a été illégalement arrêté, sans inculpation connue, sans informer les autorités de son pays (la Suède) de sa détention conformément aux protocoles internationaux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini est le directeur technique du Centre d&#39;Autonomie Numérique (Centro de Autonomía Digital) et aurait indiqué sur son compte twitter qu&#39;il se rendrait au Japon pour suivre un cours d&#39;arts martiaux, un voyage prévu il y a plus d&#39;un mois. Il a vu les propos du ministre de l&#39;Intérieur et tweeté: &amp;quot;Maria Paula Romo, ministre de l&#39;Intérieur de l&#39;Équateur, a tenu ce matin une conférence de presse au cours de laquelle elle soutenait le fait que des pirates russes vivraient en Équateur ainsi qu&#39;une personne proche de Wikileaks&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini a été développeur de logiciel toute sa vie. Il a commencé à programmer à partir de 8 ans et a créé deux langages de programmation. Il milite depuis longtemps pour le respect de la vie privée et le logiciel libre. En 2010, Computerworld en Suède l&#39;a nommé 6ème meilleur développeur du pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ses contributions :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini arrestato in Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/it/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/it/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Le persone che lavorano per il software libero e la privacy non devono essere criminalizzate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non c&#39;è nulla di criminale nel ricercare la privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, @olabini, una figura di fama mondiale nel campo del software libero e difensore dei diritti digitali e della privacy, è stato arrestato all&#39;aeroporto di Quito, in Ecuador, alle 15:20 ora locale l&#39;11 aprile 2019. Per quanto è noto, non ci sono accuse contro di lui. Ai suoi avvocati non è stato permesso incontrarlo per tutto il giorno di ieri e gli è stato concesso l&#39;accesso solo dopo essere stato detenuto per 17 ore. Alle 18:00 Gli è stato detto che lo avrebbero trasferito all&#39;Unità di Flagrancia della Procura (Unidad de Flagrancia de la Fiscalía) dell&#39;ufficio del Procuratore Generale nel centro nord di Quito per rilasciare dichiarazioni in relazione un&#39;indagine dell&#39;ufficio del Procuratore Generale provinciale a Pichincha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini, cittadino svedese che vive in Ecuador, non parla spagnolo un maniera fluente e necessita di un interprete per rilasciare qualsiasi dichiarazione. È stato detenuto illegalmente, senza accuse note e senza informare le autorità del suo paese (Svezia) riguardo alla sua detenzione come stabilito dai protocolli internazionali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;È il direttore tecnico del Center for Digital Autonomy ed aveva pubblicato sul suo account Twitter che stava per recarsi in Giappone per un corso di arti marziali, un viaggio programmato da oltre un mese. Prima di partre aveva visto le dichiarazioni del Ministro degli Interni dell&#39;Ecuador, e aveva scritto su Twitter: &amp;quot;María Paula Romo, ministro dell&#39;Interno dell&#39;Ecuador, questa mattina ha tenuto una conferenza stampa, sostenendo che ci sono hacker russi in Ecuador, e anche che c&#39;è una persona parte di Wikileaks che vive in Ecuador da diversi anni.&amp;quot;(https://twitter.com/olabini/status/1116341908371062794)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini è stato un programmatore di software per tutta la sua vita. Inizió a programmare da bambino a soli 8 anni ed è autore di due linguaggi di programmazione. Da molto tempo è un attivista nel campo della privacy on-line e Software Libero. Nel 2010 Computerworld Svezia, ha nominato Ola Bini come il 6° miglior sviluppatore del paese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha contribuito a:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini preso no Equador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/pt/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/pt/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As pessoas que trabalham com software livre e a privacidade não devem ser criminalizadas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Não há nada criminoso em querer privacidade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, @olabini, uma reconhecida figura na área do software livre mundial e defensor dos direitos digitais e a privacidade na Internet, foi detido no aeroporto de Quito, Equador às 15h20 do 11 de abril de 2019. Até aonde se sabe, não há acusações nem provas contra ele. Não foi permitido os seus advogados se reunirem com ele todo o dia de ontem (11 de abril). Às 18h00 disseram que iria mover para a Unidade de Flagrantes da Procuradoria nocentro norte de Quito para prestar declarações sobre uma investigação da Procuradoria da província de Pichincha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini, cidadão sueco residente no Equador não fala fluentemente espanhol e necessita de um intérprete para prestar qualquer declaração. Ele foi detido ilegalmente, sem acusações conhecidas, sem comunicar as autoridades de seu país (Suécia) a sua detenção como estabelecem os protocolos internacionais.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini é o Diretor Técnico do Centro de Autonomia Digital e havia publicado em sua conta de twitter que viajaria ao Japão para um curso de artes marciais, uma viagem planejada mais de um mês. Viu os comentários da ministra do Interior e twitou: “María Paula Romo, a Ministra do Interior do Equador, esta manhã realizou uma coletiva de imprensa, aonde alegava que hackers russos vivem no Equador, e que uma pessoa próxima de Wikileaks vive aquí também”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini tem sido um programador de software toda a sua vida. Começou a programar desde os 8 anos e criou duas linguagens de programação. É um ativista de privacidade e software livre por muito tempo. Em 2010, Computerworld na Suécia, nomeou como o 6º melhor desenvolvedor do país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ele contribuiu com:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini arresterad i Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/sv/ola-bini-arrest/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-12T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/sv/ola-bini-arrest/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;De som arbetar med fri programvara och integritet ska inte ses som
brottslingar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Det ligger inget olagligt i att sträva efter personlig integritet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini, @olabini, välkänd inom den världsomspännande rörelsen för
fri programvara och försvarare av digitala rättigheter och integritet
på nätet greps den 11 april 2019 kl 15:20 lokal tid på flygplatsen i
Quito, Ecuador. Såvitt det är känt finns varken formella anklagelser
eller bevis mot honom. Hans advokater fick inte möjlighet att träffa
honom på hela dagen och lyckades etablera kontakt först efter att han
suttit fängslad i 17 timmar. Först klockan 18:00 fick de uppgifter om
att han skulle överföras till en polisenhet för brottslingar som tas
på bar gärning (Unidad de Flagrancia de la Fiscalia) för att höras i
en utredning hos distriktsåklagaren i Pinchincha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini är svensk medborgare och bosatt i Ecuador. Han talar inte
flytande spanska och är i behov av tolk för att kunna yttra sig i
rättssaker. Han har på lösa grunder hållits olagligt frihetsberövad
och utan att myndigheterna i hans hemland (Sverige) har underrättats i
enlighet med internationell rätt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han är teknisk chef för Center for Digital Autonomy och ska på sitt
twitter-konto tidigare ha meddelat att han skulle resa till Japan på
en kampsportskurs, en resa planerad sedan mer än en månad. När han såg
kommentarer från Ecuadors inrikesminister twittrade han: &amp;quot;María Paula
Romo, Ecuadors inrikesminister, höll i morse en presskonferens där hon
hävdar att det finns ryska hackare i Ecuador och att det även finns en
person nära knuten till WikiLeaks som är bosatt i Ecuador sedan flera
år.&amp;quot; (https://twitter.com/olabini/status/1116341908371062794)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bini har varit mjukvaruutvecklare i hela sitt liv, sedan han började
programmera som åttaåring och har utvecklat två
programmeringsspråk. Han är mångårig aktivist och förespråkare för fri
programvara, integritet och transparens. Computerworld i Sverige
(ComputerSweden) rankade 2010 Ola Bini som nummer sex bland svenska
utvecklare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han har bidragit till:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JesCov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRuby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JtestR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yecht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAMLb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JvYAML-gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RbYAML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ribs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ActiveRecord-JDBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jatha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JOpenSSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Solidarität mit Ola Bini</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/de/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/de/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini ist Software-Entwickler und kein Krimineller&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Als Softwareentwickler, Aktivisten für freie und offene Software; als Individuen und Organisationen, die sich für die Verteidigung eines sicheren Internets einsetzen, protestieren wir entschieden gegen die anhaltende illegale Festnahme von Ola Bini in Ecuador.
Er ist ein Cyber-Security-Experte, Datenschützer, Entwickler für freie Software und netzpolitischer Aktivist.
Wir betrachten seine anhaltende Sicherungshaft als Willkür und als Angriff auf uns alle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola wurde am 11. April am Flughafen von Quito verhaftet und daran gehindert, nach Japan zu fliegen.
Seine Grundrechte wurden ihm verweigert:
Ihm wurde nicht erklärt, was ihm vorgeworfen wird; ihm wurde keine Übersetzung in seine Muttersprache – Schwedisch – angeboten, und  ohne die Möglichkeit, das schwedische Konsulat zu kontaktiren wirde er in illegal inhaftiert – eine offenkundige Verletzung der equadorianischen Verfassung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erst nach 17 Stunden bekam er Zugang zu juristischer Unterstützung.
Dreißig Stunden nach seiner Verhaftung entschied ein Gericht, dass er für 90 Tage festgehalten wird – ohne jegliche Rücksicht auf die Argumentation seiner Verteidiger, dass die gegen ihn vorgebrachten &amp;quot;Beweise&amp;quot; enorm zweifalhaft sind.
Photos von seinen elektronischen Geräten, Büchern und sogar Aufklebern wurden von der equadorianischen Polizei auf Twitter veröffentlicht.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der ecuadorianische Innenminister, María Paula Romo hat erst vor wenigen Tagen in einer Pressekonferenz behauptete russische Hacker und ein Wikileaks Aktivist würden in Ecuador leben.
Der Innenminister hat kurz nach der Festnahme gegenüber der BBC behauptet Ola hätte über mehrere Jahre Julian Assange besucht und beschuldigte Ola mit der vorherigen Regierung zu kooperieren, um die aktuelle Regierung zu destabilisieren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini ist ein Cyber-Security-Experte und Datenschutzberater im Bereich freier und offener Software, sowie ein Verteidiger der Netzpolitik.
Er ist ein schwedischer Staatsbürger, der seit sechs Jahren mit einer legalen Aufenhaltsgenehmigung in Ecuador lebt.
Er liebt Ecuador und hat sich dort sein Leben aufgebaut.
Ola war sein leben lang Software-Entwickler und hat mit 8 Jahren als Kind angefangen zu programmieren.
Er ist ein bemerkenswerter Mitwirkender einer langen Liste an Software-Projekten, darunter OTRv4 und JRuby.
Er ist ein Mitglied des Beratungsgremiums des europäischen Leuchtturmprojekts DECODE (grant nr 732546) über fortgeschrittene Kryptographie und Forschung zu &lt;em&gt;Privacy by Design&lt;/em&gt;.
Seine anhaltende Inhaftierung beeinträchtigt diese wichtige Arbeit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vor allem aber ist Ola ein liebevoller und sozial engagierter Mensch, der sein Leben einem Kampf für Recht und Gerechtigkeit gewidmet hat.
Er ist ein respektiertes und wichtiges Mitglied unserer Gemeinschaft.
Er ist einer von uns.
Seit Jahren wird unsere Gemeinschaft und unsere Arbeit verfolgt, verunglimpft und kriminalisiert.
Olas Fall zeigt, wie angreifbar und schutzlos wir sind, wie einfach wir zum Ziel werden und wie einfach Regierrungen ihre Macht missbrauchen können um uns willkürlich anzugreifen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equadors Vorgehen gegen Ola geht uns alle an.
Wenn wir es zulassen, dass Mitglieder unser Gemeinschaft öffentlich als Spione, Hacker, heimliche Verschwörer oder Eindringline hingestellt werden, dann sind wir kurz davor, alle als Gefahr für die Gesellschaft diskreditiert zu werden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deshalb müssen wir jetzt unsere Stimmen erheben und verlangen, dass Equador Ola Bini umgehend bedingungslos frei lässt – und selbstverständlich alle Verfahren gegen ihn fallen einstellt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es ist kein Verbrechen, sich für das Recht auf Privatsphäre einzusetzen.
Es ist kein Verbrechen, sich für das Recht auf freie und offene Software einzusetzen.
Ola widmet sein Leben dem Kampf für unser aller Freiheit.
Jetzt ist es an uns, für Olas Freiheit zu kämpfen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir wollen ihn zurück, wir wollen ihn in Sicherheit, wir wollen ihn in Freiheit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bitte fügt euch oder eure Organisation hinzu: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Free Ola Bini Solidarity Letter</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/en/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/en/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini is a developer, not a criminal.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As technologists, free and open source developers, and individuals and organizations working to protect the security of the Internet, we wish to protest in the strongest terms the continuing illegal detention in Ecuador of Ola Bini, a cyber-security expert, privacy consultant, free software contributor and advocate of digital rights. We see his ongoing, preventive detention as arbitrary and as an attack against us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola was detained at Quito airport on April 11 and prevented from boarding a plane to Japan. His basic rights were denied: he was not informed of the accusations against him, nor was he provided translation into his native language, Swedish, and he was kept in illegal custody without the ability to communicate with the Swedish consul, in flagrant disregard of Ecuador&#39;s constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 17 hours, he was finally granted access to legal assistance and, 30 hours after his detention, a judge ordered him to be held for 90 days pretrial detention, dismissing all arguments of the defence and presenting extremely dubious evidence against him obtained by police and the prosecution. Photographs of Ola&#39;s equipment, books, and even stickers were published by the Ecuadorian police&#39;s Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following his arrest, Ecuador&#39;s Minister of Interior, María Paula Romo—-who had just days prior held a press conference in which she claimed that Russian hackers, and a Wikileaks affiliate, were living in Ecuador--told the BBC that Ola had visited Julian Assange many times over the years, and accused of him of collaborating with former government officials to destabilise the current government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a cybersecurity expert and privacy consultant in the field of Free and open source software, as well as a defender of digital rights. He is a Swedish national, living with a valid permit in Ecuador for six years, a country he loves and where he has built his life. Ola has been a software developer his entire life, having started coding as an 8 year old child. He is a prolific contributor to a long list of projects, among them OTRv4 and JRuby, and is a member of the advisory board of the flagship European project DECODE (grant nr 732546) on advanced cryptographic and privacy by design research. His continuing detention negatively affects this important work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But above all, Ola is a loving, caring human being, who has devoted his life to what he believes is right and fair. He is a respected and important member of our community. He is one of us. For years, our community, our work has been persecuted, smeared and criminalised. Ola&#39;s case proves how vulnerable and unprotected we are, how easy it is to be targeted, and how easy it is for state actors to abuse their power arbitrarily against us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecuador&#39;s actions against Ola impact us all. If members of our community are presented to the public as spies, hackers, hidden conspirators, intruders, then we are all at risk of being seen as a danger to society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why we must raise our voices as one and demand that Ecuadorian authorities immediately release Ola Bini and unconditionally drop all charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upholding the right to privacy is not a crime. Defending the right to free and open software is not a crime. Ola devotes his life to everyone&#39;s freedom. Now, it&#39;s our turn to fight for Ola&#39;s freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want him safe, we want him back, we want him free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Please add your/your organization&#39;s name to this statement of support by emailing: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Solidara letero de Free Ola Bini</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/eo/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/eo/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini estas programisto, ne krimulo.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiel teĥnologiistoj, programistoj de libera kaj malferma kodo kaj individuoj kaj organizacioj laborantaj por protekti la sekureco de la Interreto, ni deziras plej forte protesti la daŭran areston en Ekvadoro de Ola Bini, fakulo pri cifera sekureco, konsilanto pri privateco, kontribuanto de libera programaro kaj advokato de liberaj rajtoj. Ni vidas rian daŭran antaŭgardan areston kiel arbitra kaj kiel atako kontraŭ ĉiu ni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola was detained at Quito airport on April 11 and prevented from boarding a plane to Japan. His basic rights were denied: he was not informed of the accusations against him, nor was he provided translation into his native language, Swedish, and he was kept in illegal custody without the ability to communicate with the Swedish consul, in flagrant disregard of Ecuador&#39;s constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 17 hours, he was finally granted access to legal assistance and, 30 hours after his detention, a judge ordered him to be held for 90 days pretrial detention, dismissing all arguments of the defence and presenting extremely dubious evidence against him obtained by police and the prosecution. Photographs of Ola&#39;s equipment, books, and even stickers were published by the Ecuadorian police&#39;s Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following his arrest, Ecuador&#39;s Minister of Interior, María Paula Romo—-who had just days prior held a press conference in which she claimed that Russian hackers, and a Wikileaks affiliate, were living in Ecuador--told the BBC that Ola had visited Julian Assange many times over the years, and accused of him of collaborating with former government officials to destabilise the current government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a cybersecurity expert and privacy consultant in the field of Free and open source software, as well as a defender of digital rights. He is a Swedish national, living with a valid permit in Ecuador for six years, a country he loves and where he has built his life. Ola has been a software developer his entire life, having started coding as an 8 year old child. He is a prolific contributor to a long list of projects, among them OTRv4 and JRuby, and is a member of the advisory board of the flagship European project DECODE (grant nr 732546) on advanced cryptographic and privacy by design research. His continuing detention negatively affects this important work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But above all, Ola is a loving, caring human being, who has devoted his life to what he believes is right and fair. He is a respected and important member of our community. He is one of us. For years, our community, our work has been persecuted, smeared and criminalised. Ola&#39;s case proves how vulnerable and unprotected we are, how easy it is to be targeted, and how easy it is for state actors to abuse their power arbitrarily against us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecuador&#39;s actions against Ola impact us all. If members of our community are presented to the public as spies, hackers, hidden conspirators, intruders, then we are all at risk of being seen as a danger to society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why we must raise our voices as one and demand that Ecuadorian authorities immediately release Ola Bini and unconditionally drop all charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upholding the right to privacy is not a crime. Defending the right to free and open software is not a crime. Ola devotes his life to everyone&#39;s freedom. Now, it&#39;s our turn to fight for Ola&#39;s freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ni volas rin sekura, ni volas rin returna, ni volas rin libera!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bonvolu aldoni vian/la nomon de via organizaĵo al ĉi tiu deklaro de subteno per retpoŝto: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Carta de Solidaridad por la Liberación de Ola Bini</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/es/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/es/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini es un desarrollador, no un criminal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Como tecnólogos/as, desarrolladores/as de código libre y abierto, y como personas y organizaciones que trabajan para proteger la seguridad en la Internet, queremos  denunciar en términos enérgicos la detención de Ola Bini. Ola Bini es una persona experta en ciberseguridad, consultor de privacidad, contribuye al desarrollo y defensa del código abierto y defensor de los Derechos Digitales. Vemos su detención preventiva como arbitraria y como un ataque hacia toda nuestra comunidad, y, por ende, hacia nosotros mismos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola fue detenido en el aeropuerto de Quito el 11 de Abril, tras impedirle que embarcara en un avión hacia Japón como tenía previsto desde hacia meses. Durante su detención sus derechos básicos a asistencia legal fueron denegados: no fue informado de las acusaciones en su contra; no se le facilitó un traductor a su lenguaje nativo, sueco; y fue mantenido en custodia ilegal, ya que le fue negada la posibilidad de comunicarse con el cónsul sueco, y de tener acceso a su abogado. Esto es un flagrante desprecio a lo expresado por la constitución Ecuatoriana en relación a los derechos básicos de las personas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finalmente, después de 17 horas,  se le concedió acceso a asistencia legal y, 30 horas después de su detención, un juez ordenó su detención preventiva por 90 días más al descartar todos los argumentos de la defensa de Ola y al presentar pruebas sumamente dudosas contra él obtenidas por la policía y la fiscalía. Para sumar a esta lista de irregularidades en su detención, hay que mencionar que la cuenta de twitter de la policia Ecuatoriana publicó libros, pegatinas y el equipamiento de trabajo de Ola como evidencia en su contra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Después de su arresto, la Ministra del Interior de Ecuador, María Paula Romo, --quien había realizado días antes una conferencia de prensa en la que afirmó que los piratas/&amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot; informáticos rusos y un afiliado de Wikileaks vivían en Ecuador--, le dijo a la BBC que Ola había visitado a Julian Assange en bastantes ocasiones a lo largo de los años, y lo acusó de colaborar con ex-funcionarios del gobierno para desestabilizar al gobierno actual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini es una persona experta en cyberseguridad, consultor de privacidad en el campo del código abierto y libre, así como un reconocido defensor de los Derechos Digitales. Él es un ciudadano sueco que vive en Ecuador con un permiso válido por 6 años. Vive en Ecuador pues es un país que le gusta y donde ha construido su vida.  Ola ha sido desarrollador de código toda su vida, desde los 8 años que empezó.  Su trabajo es prolífico: ha colaborado, y colabora, en una larga lista de proyectos, entre ellos, (queremos destacar por la importancia de sus contribuciones) OTR versión 4 y JRuby; y es miembro del consejo asesor del  emblemático proyecto europeo DECODE (con subvención n. 732546) sobre criptografía avanzada y la privacidad por diseño.  La comunidad ve su detención como un bloqueo importante y negativo en los proyectos que colabora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por encima de esto, Ola es una gran persona, que ha dedicado su vida a lo que cree que es correcto y justo. Es un miembro respetado e importante de nuestra comunidad. Es uno de los nuestros. Por años nuestra comunidad, nuestro trabajo ha sido perseguido, difamado y criminalizado.  El caso de Ola lo prueba una vez más: demuestra lo vulnerables y desprotegidos que estamos, lo fácilmente que podemos ser atacados y lo fácil que es para los actores estatales abusar de su poder de forma arbitraria contra nuestro trabajo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las acciones del gobierno de Ecuador en contra de Ola nos comprometen a todos. Si los miembros de nuestra comunidad son enmarcados públicamente como espías, hackers, conspiradores ocultos, intrusos, entonces, tenemos el riesgo de ser percibidos como un peligro para la sociedad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por ello, es muy importante que alcemos nuestras voces y demandemos a las autoridades ecuatorianas la liberación inmediata de Ola Bini y que le retiren incondicionalmente todos los cargos en su contra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defender el derecho a la privacidad no es un delito. Defender el derecho al software libre y abierto no es un delito. Ola dedica su vida a la libertad de todas y todos. Ahora, es nuestro turno de luchar por la libertad de Ola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Lo queremos a salvo, lo queremos de vuelta, lo queremos libre!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Por favor agrega a tu organización o a ti a esta declaración de apoyo enviando un email a: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lettre de solidarité pour la libération de Ola Bini</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/fr/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/fr/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini est un développeur, pas un criminel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En tant que technologues, développeurs de logiciels libres et open source, et en tant que personnes et organisations œuvrant pour la protection de la sécurité sur Internet, nous voulons dénoncer énergiquement la détention de Ola Bini. Ola Bini est un expert en matière de cybersécurité, consultant spécialiste de la protection de la vie privée sur Internet, il contribue au développement et à la défense de l&#39;Open Source et il est défenseur des droits numériques. Nous considérons sa détention préventive comme arbitraire et comme une attaque contre toute notre communauté, et donc contre nous-mêmes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola a été arrêté à l&#39;aéroport de Quito le 11 avril, après l&#39;avoir empêché de prendre un avion pour le Japon, comme il le prévoyait depuis des mois. Au cours de sa détention, ses droits fondamentaux à l&#39;assistance juridique ont été refusés: il n&#39;a pas été informé des accusations portées contre lui; il n&#39;a pas eu accès à un traducteur de sa langue maternelle, le suédois; et il a été gardé en arrêt illégal, car il lui a été refusé la possibilité de communiquer avec le consul de la Suède et d&#39;avoir accès à son avocat. C&#39;est un mépris flagrant envers ce qui est exprimé dans la Constitution équatorienne en ce qui concerne les droits fondamentaux des personnes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enfin, après 17 heures, il a eu accès à une assistance juridique et, 30 heures après son arrestation, un juge a ordonné sa détention préventive pour une période supplémentaire de 90 jours après avoir rejeté tous les arguments de la défense d&#39;Ola et avoir présenté des preuves hautement douteuses à son encontre fournies par la police et le bureau du procureur. Pour ajouter à cette liste d&#39;irrégularités lors de son arrêt, il convient de mentionner que le compte Twitter de la police équatorienne a publié des livres, des autocollants et le matériel de travail d&#39;Ola comme preuve contre lui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Après son arrestation, la ministre équatorienne de l&#39;Intérieur, María Paula Romo (qui avait tenu une conférence de presse quelques jours auparavant, affirmait que les pirates informatiques russes et un membre de Wikileaks vivaient en Équateur) a déclaré à la BBC qu&#39;Ola avait rendu visite à Julian Assange à plusieurs reprises au cours des années et l&#39;avait accusé de collaborer avec d&#39;anciens responsables du gouvernement Equatorien pour déstabiliser le gouvernement actuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini est un expert en cybersécurité, consultant en protection des données personnelles dans le domaine de l&#39;Open Source ainsi qu&#39;un défenseur reconnu des droits numériques. Il est citoyen suédois et réside en Equateur avec un permis valable pour 6 ans. Il vit en Equateur parce que c&#39;est un pays qu&#39;il aime et dans lequel il a construit sa vie. Ola a été développeur toute sa vie, depuis l&#39;âge de 8 ans. Son travail est prolifique: il a collaboré et collabore à une longue liste de projets, parmi lesquels (nous souhaitons souligner par l’importance de ses contributions) OTR version 4 et JRuby. Il est aussi membre du conseil qui mène le projet européen phare DECODE (avec le numéro de subvention 732546) sur la cryptographie avancée et la confidentialité de la vie privée dès la conception (privacy-by-design). La communauté considère sa détention comme un obstacle important et négatif aux projets avec lesquels il collabore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au-dessus de tout cela, Ola est une personne formidable qui a consacré sa vie à ce qu’il croit juste et correct. Il est membre respecté et important de notre communauté. Il est l&#39;un des nôtres. Pendant des années notre communauté, notre travail a été persécuté, diffamé et criminalisé. Le cas d&#39;Ola le prouve à nouveau : son cas montre à quel point nous sommes vulnérables et non protégés; la facilité avec laquelle nous pouvons être attaqués et à quel point il est facile pour les acteurs étatiques d&#39;abuser arbitrairement de leur pouvoir contre notre travail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les actions du gouvernement de l&#39;Équateur contre Ola nous engagent tous. Si les membres de notre communauté sont considérés publiquement comme des espions, des pirates, des conspirateurs cachés, des intrus, nous risquons d&#39;être perçus comme un danger pour la société.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour cette raison, il est très important que nous élevions notre voix et demandions aux autorités équatoriennes la libération immédiate d&#39;Ola Bini et qu&#39;elles retirent sans condition toutes les charges qui pèsent contre lui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Défendre le droit à la vie privée n&#39;est pas un crime. Défendre le droit aux logiciels libres et ouverts n’est pas un crime. Ola consacre sa vie à la liberté de tous. Maintenant, c&#39;est à notre tour de lutter pour la liberté d&#39;Ola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous le voulons en sécurité, nous le voulons de retour parmi nous, nous le voulons libre !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;S&#39;il te plaît, ajoute ton organisation ou toi-même à cette déclaration de support en envoyant un courrier électronique à : &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lettera di solidarietà Free Ola Bini</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/it/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/it/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini è uno sviluppatore, non un criminale.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come tecnologi, sviluppatori di Free ed Open Source software, come individui e organizzazioni che lavorano per proteggere la sicurezza di Internet, desideriamo contestare  in maniera decisa la detenzione illegale di Ola Bini in Ecuador, un esperto di sicurezza informatica, consulente per privacy, contributore di software libero e difensore dei diritti digitali. Consideriamo la prosecuzione della sua detenzione preventiva come arbitraria e come un attacco contro tutti noi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola è stato detenuto all&#39;aeroporto di Quito l&#39;11 aprile e gli è stato impedito di imbarcarsi su un aereo per il Giappone. I suoi diritti fondamentali negati: non fu informato delle accuse contro di lui, né fu garantita la traduzione nella sua lingua madre, lo svedese, e venne mantenuto sotto custodia illegale senza la capacità di comunicare con il console svedese, in flagrante disprezzo della constituzione Ecuadoriana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dopo 17 ore gli è stato concesso l&#39;accesso all&#39;assistenza legale e, a 30 ore dalla sua detenzione, un giudice ha ordinato di trattenerlo per 90 giorni di detenzione preventiva, archiviando tutti gli argomenti della difesa e presentando prove estremamente dubbie contro di lui ottenute dalla polizia e dall&#39;accusa. Le fotografie delle attrezzature, dei libri e degli adesivi di Ola sono state pubblicate dall&#39;account Twitter della polizia ecuadoriana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dopo il suo arresto, María Paula Romo, ministro dell&#39;Interno ecuadoriano, che pochi giorni prima aveva tenuto una conferenza stampa in cui sosteneva che gli hacker russi, e una affiliata di Wikileaks, vivevano in Ecuador - ha detto alla BBC che Ola aveva visitato Julian Assange molte volte nel corso degli anni, accusandolo di collaborare con ex funzionari governativi per destabilizzare l&#39;attuale governo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini è un esperto di sicurezza informatica e consulente sulla privacy nel campo del software libero e open source, nonché un difensore dei diritti digitali. È cittadino svedese, vive con un permesso valido in Ecuador da sei anni, un paese che ama e dove ha costruito la sua vita. Ola è stato uno sviluppatore di software per tutta la sua vita, avendo iniziato a programmare come un bambino di 8 anni. È un prolifico collaboratore di una lunga lista di progetti, tra cui OTRv4 e JRuby, ed è membro del advisory board del progetto europeo DECODE (concessione nr 732546) su ricerca avanzata di crittografia e privacy by design. La sua prolungata detenzione influisce negativamente su questo importante lavoro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ma soprattutto, Ola è un essere umano compassionevole e premuroso, che ha dedicato la sua vita a ciò che crede sia giusto ed equo. È un membro rispettato e importante della nostra comunità. Lui è uno di noi. Per anni, la nostra comunità, il nostro lavoro è stato perseguitato, diffamato e criminalizzato. Il caso di Ola dimostra quanto siamo vulnerabili e non protetti, quanto è facile essere presi di mira e quanto è facile per istituzioni nazionali di abusare del loro potere contro di noi arbitrariamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le azioni dell&#39;Ecuador contro Ola hanno un impatto su tutti noi. Se i membri della nostra comunità vengono presentati al pubblico come spie, hacker, cospiratori nascosti, infiltrati allora siamo tutti a rischio di essere visti come un pericolo per la società.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecco perché dobbiamo unire le nostre voci per chiedere alle autorità ecuadoriane di rilasciare immediatamente Ola Bini e lasciare cadere incondizionatamente tutte le accuse contro di lui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sostenere il diritto alla privacy non è un crimine. Difendere il diritto di software libero e aperto non è un crimine. Ola dedica la sua vita alla libertà di tutti. Ora, è il nostro turno di combattere per la libertà di Ola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo vogliamo al sicuro, lo rivogliamo indietro, lo vogliamo libero!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I firmatari&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Aggiungi il nome della tua organizzazione alla presente dichiarazione di supporto tramite email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Carta de Solidaridade pela Liberdade de Ola Bini</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/pt/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/pt/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini é um desenvolvedor, não é um criminoso.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Como tecnólogos/as, desenvolvedores/as de código livre e aberto, e como pessoas e organizações que trabalham para proteger a segurança na Internet, queremos denunciar e repudiar a prisão ilegal de Ola Bini no Equador. Ola Bini é um especialista em cibersegurança, consultor de privacidade, desenvolvedor e defensor do código aberto e defensor dos Direitos Digitais. Vemos a sua prisão preventiva como arbitrária e como um ataque contra toda nossa comunidade, e, portanto, contra nós mesmos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola foi detido no aeroporto de Quito no dia 11 de Abril, após impedirem de embarcar em um avião para Japão como havia planejado há meses. Durante sua detenção seus direitos básicos a assistência legal foram negados: não foi informado sobre as acusações contra ele; não forneceram um tradutor para a sua língua nativa, língua sueca; e foi mantido sob custódia ilegal, já que foi negada a possibilidade de se comunicar com o consul sueco, e de ter acesso a seu advogado. Este é um flagrante desrespeito ao expressado pela constituição Equatoriana em relação aos direitos básicos das pessoas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finalmente, depois de 17 horas, foi concedido acesso a assistência legal e, 30 horas depois de sua detenção, um juiz ordenou a sua prisão preventiva por 90 dias, descartando todos os argumentos da defesa de Ola e apresentando provas extremamente duvidosas obtidas pela polícia e a procuradoria. Para somar a esta lista de irregularidades da sua detenção, é necessário mencionar que a conta de twitter da polícia Equatoriana publicou fotografias de livros, adesivos e o equipamento de trabalho de Ola como evidências.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depois de sua prisão, a Ministra do Interior de Equador, María Paula Romo, -- a qual dias antes havia realizado uma conferência de imprensa afirmando que os /&amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot; russos e um membro de Wikileaks viviam no Equador--, disse para a BBC que Ola havia visitado Julian Assange em várias ocasiões ao longo dos anos, e o acusou de colaborar com ex-funcionários do governo para desestabilizar o governo atual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini é um especialista em cibersegurança, consultor de privacidade no campo do código aberto e livre, assim como um reconhecido defensor dos Direitos Digitais. Ele é um cidadão sueco que vive no Equador com visto válido por 6 anos. Vive no Equador pois é um país que ama e onde construiu sua vida. Ola é desenvolvedor de software toda a sua vida, iniciando na programação quando era uma criança de 8 anos. Ele é um grande contribuidor de uma varidade de projetos, entre eles, OTR versão 4 e JRuby, e é membro do conselho assessor do emblemático projeto europeu DECODE (registro n. 732546) sobre criptografia avançada e a privacidade por design. A sua detenção afeta negativamente esse importante trabalho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mas além disso, Ola é uma pessoa amável e carinhosa, que dedica a sua vida naquilo que acredita que é correto e justo. É um membro respeitado e importante de nossa comunidade. É um dos nossos. Por anos nossa comunidade, nosso trabalho tem sido perseguido, difamado e criminalizado. O caso de Ola prova mais uma vez o quão vulneráveis e desprotegidos estamos, quão fácil podemos ser atacados e quão fácil é para agentes estatais abusarem de seu poder de forma arbitrária contra o nosso trabalho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ações do governo de Equador contra Ola impacta contra todos nós. Se os membros de nossa comunidade são apresentado publicamente como espiões, hackers, conspiradores ocultos, intrusos, então, todos corremos o risco de sermos identificados como um perigo para a sociedade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por isso é muito importante que levantar as nossas vozes e demandar que as autoridades equatorianas libertem imediatamente Ola Bini e que retirem incondicionalmente todas as acusações contra ele.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defender o direito a privacidade não é um crime. Defender o direito ao software livre e aberto não é um crime. Ola dedica a sua vida a libertade de todas e todos. Agora, é nossa vez de lutar pela liberdade de Ola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nós queremos ele seguro, nós queremos ele de volta, nós queremos ele livre!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Por favor adicione a sua organização/você nesta declaração de apoio enviando um email para: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Brev till stöd för Ola Binis frigivande</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/sv/statement/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-16T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/sv/statement/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini är utvecklare, inte brottsling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Som tekniker, utvecklare av fri och öppen programvara och som
individer och organisationer som arbetar med att skydda säkerheten på
internet, protesterar vi starkt mot det olagliga
frihetsberövandet av Ola Bini i Ecuador. Ola är expert på IT-säkerhet,
privacy-konsult, utvecklare av fri programvara och förespråkare för
digitala rättigheter. Vi ser häktningen av Ola som
godtycklig och som en attack mot oss alla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola greps på flygplatsen i Quito den 11 april och hindrades att gå
ombord på ett plan till Japan. Hans grundläggande rättigheter
har kränkts: han informerades inte om anklagelserna mot honom och han
fick inte heller tolkning till svenska. Vidare
kvarhölls han olagligt utan möjlighet att kommunicera med det svenska
konsulatet, vilket är ett uppenbart åsidosättande av Ecuadors konstitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Först efter 17 timmar fick han juridisk hjälp och 30
timmar efter att han gripits beordrade en domare att han skulle
häktas i 90 dagar i väntan på domstolsförhandlingar. Alla argument
från försvaret avfärdades och polis och åklagare presenterade högst
tvivelaktig bevisning mot honom. Fotografier av Olas utrustning,
böcker och till och med klistermärken publicerades på
polisens Twitter-konto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efter gripandet anklagade María Paula Romo, Ecuadors inrikesminister,
Ola för att samarbeta med tidigare regeringstjänstemän för att
destabilisera den nuvarande regeringen. Hon berättade för BBC att Ola
hade besökt Julian Assange många gånger genom åren. Bara ett par dagar
innan hade hon hållit en presskonferens där hon hävdat att ryska
hackers, och en person nära WikiLeaks, bodde i Ecuador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini är expert på IT-säkerhet och privacy-konsult inom fri och öppen
programvara, och en förespråkare av digitala rättigheter. Han är
svensk och har med giltigt tillstånd i sex år bott i Ecuador,
ett land som han älskar och där han har skapat sig ett liv. Ola
har varit mjukvaruutvecklare i hela sitt liv och började programmera redan
som åttaåring. Han är en framstående bidragsgivare till en lång rad av
projekt, bland andra OTRv4 och JRuby, och medlem av den rådgivande
panelen för det europeiska flaggskeppsprojektet DECODE (anslag 732546)
för avancerad kryptografi och forskning inom &amp;quot;privacy by design&amp;quot;. Hans
fängslande påverkar detta viktiga arbete negativt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men inte minst, är Ola en älskvärd och omtänksam människa som har
vigt sitt liv åt vad han tycker är rätt och riktigt. Han är en
respekterad och viktig medlem av vår gemenskap. Han är en av oss. I
flera år har vår gemenskap och vårt arbete förföljts, svärtats ned,
och kriminaliserats. Olas fall visar hur sårbara och oskyddade vi är,
hur lätt det är att bli en måltavla samt hur lätt det är för
statliga aktörer att godtyckligt missbruka sin makt mot oss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecuadors agerande mot Ola har stor påverkan på oss alla. Om
medlemmar ur vår gemenskap offentligt framställs som spioner, hackers,
hemliga konspiratörer och inkräktare, så riskerar vi alla att ses som
en fara för samhället.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Därför måste vi höja våra röster och kräva att myndigheterna i Ecuador
omedelbart släpper Ola Bini fri och lägger ner alla
anklagelser mot honom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Att försvara rättigheterna till personlig integritet är inte ett
brott. Att försvara rätten till fri och öppen programvara är inget
brott. Ola arbetar för allas vår frihet. Nu är det vår tur att
arbeta för Olas frihet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vi vill att han ska vara i säkerhet, vi vill ha honom tillbaka och vi
vill att han ska få sin frihet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#FreeOlaBini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Skriv under vårt stöduttalande&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skriv under med ditt eller din organisations namn genom att mejla
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:signatures@freeolabini.org?subject=Signature+#FreeOlaBini&amp;amp;body=Let%20us%20know%20if%20you%20are%20signing%20as%20an%20organization%20or%20personally.%20In%20both%20cases%20send%20us%20a%20link%20to%20your%20website%20with%20statement%20of%20support%20for%20Ola,%20or%20your%20twitter%20profile.%20In%20case%20of%20an%20organization%20please%20send%20a%20logo%20for%20white%20background(png/jpg).%0D%0A%0D%0Aname:%0D%0Aurl:%0D%0Aimage:%0D%0A&quot;&gt;signatures@freeolabini.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini über seine willkürliche Haft in El Inca, Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/de/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-17T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/de/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Eine Nachricht von Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Als erstes möchte ich meinen internationalen Unterstützern danken.
Ich habe gehört dass mein Fall Aufmerksamkeit und Unterstützung überall auf der Welt erfährt und dafür bin ich so dankbar, dass mir die Worte fehlen.
An meine Freunde, meine Familie und die, die mir am nächsten sind: All meine Liebe – ich denke die ganze Zeit an euch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ich glaube fest an das Recht auf Privatsphäre.
Ohne Privatsphäre können wir keine Selbstbestimmtheit entwickeln – und ohne Selbstbestimmtheit sind wir Sklaven.
Deshalb habe ich mein Leben diesem Kapf gewidmet.
Überwachung ist eine Bedrohung für uns alle, wir müssen sie stoppen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Mächtigen dieser Welt führen einen Kampf gegen das freie Wissen.
Gegen mich wurde eine Anklage konstruiert aufgrund der Bücher, die ich lese und der Technologien, die ich nutze.
Wir kennen das als Orwell&#39;sche &lt;em&gt;Gedankenverbrechen&lt;/em&gt;.
Das können wir nicht zulassen.
Diese Welt wird uns immer mehr einengen, bis wir keinen Freiraum mehr haben.
Wenn Equador damit durchkommt, dann schaffen das auch andere.
Wir müssen diese Entwicklung jetzt stoppen, bevor es zu spät ist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ich bin mir sicher, dass es für alle klar wird, dass meine Anklage substanzlos ist und in sich zusammenbrechen wird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ich kann mir eine Kritik am equadorianischen Gefängnissystem nicht verkneifen.
Meine Gefangenschaft ist zwar unter vergleichsweise humanen Bedingungen, aber die Zustände hier sind immer noch verabscheuenswürdig.
Dieses Land braucht dringend eine Gefängnisreform.
Meine Gedanken gehen an meine Mitgefangenen in Ecuador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ola Bini’s statement from arbitrary detention at El Inca Prison, Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/en/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-17T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/en/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I want to thank all my supporters out there. I&#39;ve been told about the attention this case is getting from all the world, and I appreciate it more than I can say. To my friends, family and nearest ones: all my love - you&#39;re constantly in my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe strongly in the right to privacy. Without privacy, we can&#39;t have agency, and without agency we are slaves. That&#39;s why I have dedicated my life to this struggle. Surveillance is a threat to us all, we must stop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaders of the world are waging a war against knowledge. The case against me is based on the books I&#39;ve read and the technology I have. This is Orwellian - ThoughtCrime. We can&#39;t let this happen. The world will close in closer and closer on us, until we have nothing left. If Ecuador can do this, so can others. We have to stop this idea now, before it&#39;s too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m confident it will be obvious that there&#39;s no substance to this case, and that it will collapse into nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t avoid saying a word about the Ecuadorian penal system. I&#39;m being held under the best circumstances and it&#39;s still despicable. There needs to be serious reform. My thoughts go out to all fellow inmates in Ecuador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Deklaro de Ola Bini pri arbitra aresto en maliberejo El Inca, Ekvadoro</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/eo/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-17T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/eo/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unue mi volas danki al ĉiuj miaj subtenantoj ĉie eksteraj. Oni informis al mi pri la atento, kiun ĉi afero ricevas el la tuta mondo, kaj mi aprecas ĝin pli ol mi eblas diri. Al miaj amikoj, familio kaj pli proksimiaj al mi: ĉiun mian amon --- vi estas daŭre en miaj pensoj.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mi firme kredas en la rajto al privateco. Sen privateco ni ne povas havi povon, kaj sen povo ni estas sklavoj. Tio estas kial mi dediĉis mia vivo por ĉi tiu batalo. Rigardado estas minaco por ĉiuj ni, ni devas ĉesigi ĝin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La estroj de la mondo estas batalante kontraŭ la kono. La juĝafero kontraŭ mi baziĝas sur la libroj kiujn mi legis kaj la teĥnologio kiun mi havas. Tio estas orvela (&lt;em&gt;Orwellian&lt;/em&gt;) --- PensoKrimo. Ni ne povas lasi, ke tio okazas. La mondo malfermos pli kaj pli por ni, ĝis ni nenion havas. Se Ekvadoro povas fari tion, tiel povas aliaj. Ni devas ĉesigi ĉi tiun ideon nun, antaŭ estas tro malfrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mi certas, ke estos evidenta, ke ne estas substanco en ĉi tiu juĝafero kaj ke ĝi disfalos al nenio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mi ne povas eviti diri ion pri la ekvadora puna sistemo. Mi estas entenitaj sur la plej bonaj situacioj kaj ankoraŭ estas malnobla. Devas okazi grava reformo. Miaj pensoj iras al ĉiuj aliaj malliberuloj en Ekvadoro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dichiarazione di Ola Bini sulla detenzione arbitraria nella prigione di El Inca, Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/it/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-17T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/it/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In primo luogo, voglio ringraziare tutti i miei sostenitori là fuori. Mi è stato detto dell&#39;attenzione che questo caso sta ricevendo da tutto il mondo e lo apprezzo più di quanto possa esprimere. Ai miei amici, familiari e vicini: tutto il mio amore - siete costantemente nei miei pensieri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credo fermamente nel diritto alla privacy. Senza privacy perdiamo la libertà di agire, e senza l&#39;azione siamo schiavi. Ecco perché ho dedicato la mia vita a questa lotta. La vigilanza è una minaccia per tutti noi, dobbiamo fermarla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leader del mondo stanno conducendo una guerra contro la conoscenza. Il caso contro di me si basa sui libri che ho letto e sulla tecnologia che ho. Questo è un ThoughtCrime Orwelliano. Non possiamo permettere che questo accada. Il mondo si chiuderà sempre più vicino attorno a noi, finché non ci sarà rimasto nulla. Se l&#39;Ecuador può fare questo, anche gli altri possono farlo. Dobbiamo fermare questa idea ora, prima che sia troppo tardi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sono certo che sarà ovvio che non c&#39;è alcun fondamento in questo caso e che collasserà nel nulla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non posso evitare di dire una parola sul sistema penale ecuadoriano. Sono detenuto nelle migliori condizioni ed è ancora spregevole. Deve essere fatta una seria riforma. I miei pensieri vanno a tutti i compagni detenuti in Ecuador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Carta de Ola Bini da prisão de El Inca, Equador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/pt/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-17T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/pt/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primeiro, quero agradecer a todas as pessoas que estão me apoiando aí fora. Me contaram da atenção que este caso despertou no mundo todo e isso é algo que agradeço mais do posso expressar com palavras. A minha família, meus amigos, a todos os que estão próximos, mando todo meu amor. Tenho sempre em meus pensamentos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acredito firmemente no direito a privacidade. Sem privacidade não é possível agir e sem agir, somos escravos. Por isso dediquei a minha vida a esta luta. A vigilância é uma ameaça para todos nós, e nós devemos pará-la.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Os líderes do mundo estão promovendo uma guerra contra o conhecimento. O caso contra mim é baseado nos livros que eu tenho lido e da tecnologia que eu tenho. Isso é algo Orwelliano - uma Crimideia. Não podemos deixar que isso aconteça. O mundo se fechará mais e mais ao nosso redor até que não nos reste mais nada. Se o Equador pode fazer isso, outros também podem. Temos que parar essa ideia agora, antes que isso seja tarde demais.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eu tenho confiança que será óbvio que não há substância para esse caso, e que isso acabará em nada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Não posso evitar de falar algo sobre o sistema penal equatoriano. Eu estou sendo detido nas melhores circunstâncias e ainda assim é terrível. É necessário uma séria reforma. Meus pensamentos vão para todos os demais presos no Equador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Uttalande av Ola Bini, godtyckligt häktad i El Inca-fängelset, Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/sv/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-17T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/sv/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Först av allt vill jag tacka för allt stöd där ute. Man har berättat för mig
om vilken uppmärksamhet som det här fallet fått över hela världen och jag
kan inte med ord beskriva hur mycket jag uppskattar det. Till mina
vänner, min familj och mina närmaste: all min kärlek till er -- ni
finns ständigt i mina tankar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jag tror starkt på rätten till personlig integritet. Utan integritet har
vi ingen handlingsfrihet och utan handlingsfrihet är vi
slavar. Därför har jag vigt mitt liv åt den här
kampen. Övervakning är ett hot mot oss alla och den måste stoppas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Världens ledare för ett krig mot kunskap. Mitt fall
baseras på vilka böcker jag läser och vilka teknikprylar jag
äger. Det hela är Orwellskt -- krimtänk. Vi får inte låta det här
hända. Världen kryper närmare och närmare inpå oss, tills vi inte har
någonting kvar. Om Ecuador kan göra så här, så kan också andra.
Vi måste stoppa de här tankegångarna nu, innan det är för sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jag är övertygad om att det kommer att visa sig att det här fallet
saknar all substans, och att luften kommer att gå ur ballongen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jag måste också säga något om det ecuadorianska straffrättsliga systemet. Jag
hålls fängslad under de bästa förhållanden men det är ändå avskyvärt.
Här krävs genomgripande reform. Mina tankar går till
alla mina medfångar i Ecuador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Declaración de Ola Bini por arresto arbitrario desde la cárcel del Inca, Ecuador</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/es/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-18T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/es/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primero, quiero agradecer a todas las personas que me están apoyando ahí afuera. Me contaron de la atención que este caso ha despertado en todo el mundo y eso es algo que aprecio más de lo que puedo expresar con palabras. A mi familia, mis amigos, a todos los que están cerca, les mando todo mi amor. Los tengo siempre en mis pensamientos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creo firmemente en el derecho a la privacidad. Sin privacidad no hay agencia y sin agencia, somos esclavos. Por eso he dedicado mi vida a esta lucha. La vigilancia es una amenaza para todos nosotros. Debe parar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los lideres del mundo están librando una guerra contra el conocimiento. El caso en mi contra se basa en los libros que he leído y en la tecnología que tengo. Eso es un crimen solo desde un pensamiento orwelliano. No podemos dejar que esto suceda. El mundo se cerrará más y más a nuestro alrededor hasta que no nos quede nada. Si Ecuador puede hacer esto, también pueden hacerlo otros. Tenemos que detener esto antes de que sea demasiado tarde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tengo confianza en que será obvio que este caso no puede sustanciarse y se derrumbará.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No puedo evitar decir algo sobre el sistema penal ecuatoriano. Estoy detenido en las mejores circunstancias y aún así es terrible. Se requiere una reforma en serio. Mis pensamientos están con todos los demás presos en el Ecuador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Déclaration d&#39;Ola Bini suite à son arrestation arbitraire depuis la prison de El Inca, en Équateur</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/fr/statement-from-ola/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-18T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/fr/statement-from-ola/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tout d’abord, je tiens à remercier toutes les personnes qui me soutiennent. On m&#39;a parlé de l&#39;attention que cette affaire a suscité dans le monde entier et c&#39;est quelque chose que j&#39;apprécie plus que ce que je pourrais exprimer avec mes mots. À ma famille, mes amis, à tous ceux qui sont proches, je vous envoie tout mon amour. Je vous ai toujours dans mes pensées.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je crois fermement au droit à la vie privée. Sans vie privée, il n&#39;y a pas d&#39;agentivité et sans agentivité, nous sommes des esclaves. C&#39;est pourquoi j&#39;ai consacré ma vie à cette lutte. La surveillance est une menace pour nous tous. Ça doit s&#39;arrêter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les leaders du monde mènent une guerre contre le savoir. Cette affaire contre moi est basée sur les livres que j&#39;ai lus et sur la technologie dont je dispose. C&#39;est orwellien - crime de pensée. Nous ne pouvons pas laisser que cela arrive. Le monde se reserre de plus en plus autour de nous jusqu&#39;à ce qu&#39;il ne nous reste plus rien. Si l’Équateur peut le faire, d’autres le peuvent aussi. Nous devons arrêter cela avant qu&#39;il ne soit trop tard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je suis convaincu qu&#39;il sera évident que cette affaire ne peut pas se justifier et va donc s&#39;effondrer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je ne peux pas m&#39;empêcher de dire quelque chose sur le système pénal équatorien. Je suis détenu dans les meilleures conditions et pourtant c&#39;est terrible. Une réforme sérieuse est nécessaire. Mes pensées vont à tous les prisonniers en Équateur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ola Bini&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to the Prime Minister of Sweden</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/de/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/de/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Swedish national Ola Metodius Bini, a free software developer, was arrested in Quito (Ecuador). He has been living in the Republic of Ecuador for the past six years. Ola Bini is now serving a 90-day pretrial detention. He has not been afforded bail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Ola Bini has drawn worldwide concern. UN Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008&quot;&gt;David Kaye&lt;/a&gt; said that ‘nothing in this story connects Ola Bini to any crime’. Further, he said, ‘the govt of Ecuador must demonstrate more than that or this looks like an arbitrary detention’. The Organisation of American State’s Special Rapporteur for Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504&quot;&gt;Edison Lanza&lt;/a&gt;, added, ‘I share the Rapporteur David Kaye’s concern around the arrest and detention of digital activist Ola Bini’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152&quot;&gt;Article 19 have publicly&lt;/a&gt; echoed this concern and are closely monitoring the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Ola Bini was going to Japan for a martial arts training course, which he had advertised on twitter a week before. He was detained by the Ecuadorian police. In violation of due process, the police did not contact the Swedish authorities. This process is part of the standards of Ecuadorian law. After 15 hours of his initial detention, they made the contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini’s human rights have been violated repeatedly by the police, by the Ministry of the Interior, by the Attorney General’s office and by the judge in charge of the case. The agents who initially detained him did not have a valid warrant. He was denied access to his lawyers for 17 hours. He was not permitted to have a translator – even though his Spanish is rudimentary. He was not informed of the charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini was held at the airport for more than eight hours. In violation of Ecuadorian law, he was not transferred to the police facilities. The police then took him to his home, where they coerced him to allow access. Finally, he was taken to a facility abandoned by the judicial police, where he spent the night. By that time, he still did not have any access to legal advice or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning – on April 12 – Ola Bini was transferred to the Prosecutor&#39;s Office, where he remained for a further 12 hours before a hearing. For a total of 17 hours Ola Bini was not allowed legal advice or food. His lawyers report that they were harassed and threatened by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the hearing, the prosecutor offered no evidence against Ola Bini. Based on the Ecuadorian Penal Code, he was accused of one very serious crime – attacking the integrity of computer systems. Despite the lack of any evidence, the judge placed Ola Bini in pretrial detention for 90 days. There was no bail hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the process is politically motivated. Fabricated charges, with no evidence, have been brought against an innocent man. He has been caught in a dispute that does not concern him and with which he is not involved at all. There is not a single piece of evidence that incriminates him. Ola Bini sits in an Ecuadoran prison, denied bail, and with no guarantees of due process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a globally respected figure in the free software community, and a renowned activist for the right to privacy. In 2010, Computerworld magazine named him as Sweden&#39;s 6th best developer. He is a member of various European and international networks for free software and privacy, and he participates in projects of the highest level, some of them sponsored by the European Commission. Ola has never expressed any views that would in any way be a threat to the Ecuadorian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an advocate and an activist for the right to privacy, Ola has visited Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian Embassy in London several times. However, he does not work for Wikileaks, nor has he ever worked for them. Any allegation that he is conspiring against the Ecuadorian government and its computer systems is false and ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appeal to the Swedish Government to take firm, immediate action. So far, the Swedish Government&#39;s efforts have been limited to the presence of the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito.  While we are grateful that the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito involved himself we would ask you and the government to lift this to a political level, since it seems to be a political reason behind the arrest. We are sure that the misunderstanding about who Ola is and what he does could quickly be resolved. The Swedish Society and the Government of Sweden are recognized worldwide as active defenders and promoters of human rights and freedom of expression. His family, his friends, his colleagues, call on the Swedish government to intercede for Ola before the Ecuador authorities, demand respect for the law and for Ola’s human rights, and to facilitate his safe immediate return to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respectfully,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerned citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt; / Actress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Musician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25 co-founder, Professor of Economics – University of Athens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundahti Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Glover&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Institute Professor (emeritus) MIT, Laureate Professor U. of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1980, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt; / writer and researcher on social implications of technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosopher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / French MP and President of the Parliamentary Group France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Podemos, presidential candidate, Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1976, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Software Development Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Director - Democracia en Red -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; / Lawyer of Milagros de Sala and diverse causes of defense of human rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; / President of the Argentine League for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; / CTEP leader and Patria Grande Front member. Coordinator of the dialogues of popular movements with Pope Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; / Patria Grande Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; / President of La FEC, Foundation Europe of the Citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Australian Senator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; / Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25, and Co-Founder World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; / Political Innovation Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Evengelical Front for a State of Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of the International Committee of the Brazilian Association of Jurists for Democracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor at UNIFESP University Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; / Dominican friar and writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist - Universidade de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; / National Direction of MST and of Brazil Popular Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; / MST and Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; / Theologian, Philosopher and Member of the International Earth Charta Comission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Psychologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; / Former minister for human rights and former coordinator of the National Truth Commision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; / Historian and Teacher - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - University, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; / Author and co-editor, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; / Danish programmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; / Muralist Painter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; / Popular education professor, photographer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; / Technologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; / University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; / Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Whistleblower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; / Russell Tribunal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Miranda&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; / Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Left Party Spokesperson on the Committee on International Relations of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; / Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Regional Parliament of Thuringia (Mitglied des Landtages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; / Renewable Freedom Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Vice Chair Left Parliamentary Group of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; / Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytri Kleiner&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; / Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Coordinating Collective in DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist, Activist, MEP candidate MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Former parliamentarian for the Civic Movement &amp;amp; Pirate Party in the Icelandic Parliament &amp;amp; chairman for IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; / Chairman of The Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder, People’s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / President Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chandra&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO Barcelona and DECODE project lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; / Co-Founder European Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; / Laureate UN Human Rights Award 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; / PhD Student/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary, National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher - New Frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; / President of Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; / UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Coordinator of United Left Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Human Rights Lawyer, Co-founder of Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary of the Spanish Communist Party, Human Rights Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; / First Deputy Mayor Barcelona City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Secretary of the Parliamentary Group of Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; / Vice President of the Party of the European Left (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and International Secretary of Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yolanda Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; / MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling Dahl&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO / fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / CEO at fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Amroussia&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamma Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / GS (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heikel Belkacem&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jilani Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist and Decode advisory panel member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad&lt;/strong&gt; / Chancellor&#39;s Professor in the Department of Comparative Literature, University of California (Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist/Activist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Veterans for Peace and former UN Diplomat, who resigned in 2003 in opposition to the US war on Iraq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; / Novelist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; / Attorney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; / City University of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; / former CIA Counterterrorism Officer and former Senior Investigator, US Senate Foreign Relations Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; / Film Producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; / CEPR, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Legal Director, Software Freedom Law Centre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of ThoughtWorks, now retired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; / Principal Engineer, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William J. Barber II&lt;/strong&gt; / Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor of History and Africana Studies, Williams College, Massachusetts USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; / Communications Director - torproject. Actor, Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; / Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Technical Director at NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliations are listed for identification purposes&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to the Prime Minister of Sweden</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/en/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/en/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Swedish national Ola Metodius Bini, a free software developer, was arrested in Quito (Ecuador). He has been living in the Republic of Ecuador for the past six years. Ola Bini is now serving a 90-day pretrial detention. He has not been afforded bail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Ola Bini has drawn worldwide concern. UN Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008&quot;&gt;David Kaye&lt;/a&gt; said that ‘nothing in this story connects Ola Bini to any crime’. Further, he said, ‘the govt of Ecuador must demonstrate more than that or this looks like an arbitrary detention’. The Organisation of American State’s Special Rapporteur for Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504&quot;&gt;Edison Lanza&lt;/a&gt;, added, ‘I share the Rapporteur David Kaye’s concern around the arrest and detention of digital activist Ola Bini’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152&quot;&gt;Article 19 have publicly&lt;/a&gt; echoed this concern and are closely monitoring the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Ola Bini was going to Japan for a martial arts training course, which he had advertised on twitter a week before. He was detained by the Ecuadorian police. In violation of due process, the police did not contact the Swedish authorities. This process is part of the standards of Ecuadorian law. After 15 hours of his initial detention, they made the contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini’s human rights have been violated repeatedly by the police, by the Ministry of the Interior, by the Attorney General’s office and by the judge in charge of the case. The agents who initially detained him did not have a valid warrant. He was denied access to his lawyers for 17 hours. He was not permitted to have a translator – even though his Spanish is rudimentary. He was not informed of the charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini was held at the airport for more than eight hours. In violation of Ecuadorian law, he was not transferred to the police facilities. The police then took him to his home, where they coerced him to allow access. Finally, he was taken to a facility abandoned by the judicial police, where he spent the night. By that time, he still did not have any access to legal advice or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning – on April 12 – Ola Bini was transferred to the Prosecutor&#39;s Office, where he remained for a further 12 hours before a hearing. For a total of 17 hours Ola Bini was not allowed legal advice or food. His lawyers report that they were harassed and threatened by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the hearing, the prosecutor offered no evidence against Ola Bini. Based on the Ecuadorian Penal Code, he was accused of one very serious crime – attacking the integrity of computer systems. Despite the lack of any evidence, the judge placed Ola Bini in pretrial detention for 90 days. There was no bail hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the process is politically motivated. Fabricated charges, with no evidence, have been brought against an innocent man. He has been caught in a dispute that does not concern him and with which he is not involved at all. There is not a single piece of evidence that incriminates him. Ola Bini sits in an Ecuadoran prison, denied bail, and with no guarantees of due process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a globally respected figure in the free software community, and a renowned activist for the right to privacy. In 2010, Computerworld magazine named him as Sweden&#39;s 6th best developer. He is a member of various European and international networks for free software and privacy, and he participates in projects of the highest level, some of them sponsored by the European Commission. Ola has never expressed any views that would in any way be a threat to the Ecuadorian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an advocate and an activist for the right to privacy, Ola has visited Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian Embassy in London several times. However, he does not work for Wikileaks, nor has he ever worked for them. Any allegation that he is conspiring against the Ecuadorian government and its computer systems is false and ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appeal to the Swedish Government to take firm, immediate action. So far, the Swedish Government&#39;s efforts have been limited to the presence of the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito.  While we are grateful that the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito involved himself we would ask you and the government to lift this to a political level, since it seems to be a political reason behind the arrest. We are sure that the misunderstanding about who Ola is and what he does could quickly be resolved. The Swedish Society and the Government of Sweden are recognized worldwide as active defenders and promoters of human rights and freedom of expression. His family, his friends, his colleagues, call on the Swedish government to intercede for Ola before the Ecuador authorities, demand respect for the law and for Ola’s human rights, and to facilitate his safe immediate return to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respectfully,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerned citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt; / Actress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Musician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25 co-founder, Professor of Economics – University of Athens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundahti Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Glover&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Institute Professor (emeritus) MIT, Laureate Professor U. of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1980, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt; / writer and researcher on social implications of technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosopher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / French MP and President of the Parliamentary Group France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Podemos, presidential candidate, Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1976, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Software Development Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Director - Democracia en Red -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; / Lawyer of Milagros de Sala and diverse causes of defense of human rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; / President of the Argentine League for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; / CTEP leader and Patria Grande Front member. Coordinator of the dialogues of popular movements with Pope Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; / Patria Grande Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; / President of La FEC, Foundation Europe of the Citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Australian Senator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; / Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25, and Co-Founder World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; / Political Innovation Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Evengelical Front for a State of Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of the International Committee of the Brazilian Association of Jurists for Democracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor at UNIFESP University Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; / Dominican friar and writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist - Universidade de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; / National Direction of MST and of Brazil Popular Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; / MST and Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; / Theologian, Philosopher and Member of the International Earth Charta Comission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Psychologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; / Former minister for human rights and former coordinator of the National Truth Commision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; / Historian and Teacher - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - University, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; / Author and co-editor, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; / Danish programmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; / Muralist Painter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; / Popular education professor, photographer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; / Technologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; / University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; / Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Whistleblower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; / Russell Tribunal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Miranda&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; / Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Left Party Spokesperson on the Committee on International Relations of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; / Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Regional Parliament of Thuringia (Mitglied des Landtages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; / Renewable Freedom Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Vice Chair Left Parliamentary Group of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; / Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytri Kleiner&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; / Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Coordinating Collective in DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist, Activist, MEP candidate MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Former parliamentarian for the Civic Movement &amp;amp; Pirate Party in the Icelandic Parliament &amp;amp; chairman for IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; / Chairman of The Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder, People’s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / President Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chandra&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO Barcelona and DECODE project lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; / Co-Founder European Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; / Laureate UN Human Rights Award 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; / PhD Student/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary, National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher - New Frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; / President of Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; / UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Coordinator of United Left Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Human Rights Lawyer, Co-founder of Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary of the Spanish Communist Party, Human Rights Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; / First Deputy Mayor Barcelona City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Secretary of the Parliamentary Group of Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; / Vice President of the Party of the European Left (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and International Secretary of Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yolanda Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; / MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling Dahl&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO / fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / CEO at fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Amroussia&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamma Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / GS (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heikel Belkacem&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jilani Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist and Decode advisory panel member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad&lt;/strong&gt; / Chancellor&#39;s Professor in the Department of Comparative Literature, University of California (Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist/Activist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Veterans for Peace and former UN Diplomat, who resigned in 2003 in opposition to the US war on Iraq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; / Novelist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; / Attorney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; / City University of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; / former CIA Counterterrorism Officer and former Senior Investigator, US Senate Foreign Relations Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; / Film Producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; / CEPR, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Legal Director, Software Freedom Law Centre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of ThoughtWorks, now retired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; / Principal Engineer, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William J. Barber II&lt;/strong&gt; / Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor of History and Africana Studies, Williams College, Massachusetts USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; / Communications Director - torproject. Actor, Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; / Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Technical Director at NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliations are listed for identification purposes&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Letero al la sveda ĉefministro</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/eo/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/eo/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Swedish national Ola Metodius Bini, a free software developer, was arrested in Quito (Ecuador). He has been living in the Republic of Ecuador for the past six years. Ola Bini is now serving a 90-day pretrial detention. He has not been afforded bail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Ola Bini has drawn worldwide concern. UN Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008&quot;&gt;David Kaye&lt;/a&gt; said that ‘nothing in this story connects Ola Bini to any crime’. Further, he said, ‘the govt of Ecuador must demonstrate more than that or this looks like an arbitrary detention’. The Organisation of American State’s Special Rapporteur for Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504&quot;&gt;Edison Lanza&lt;/a&gt;, added, ‘I share the Rapporteur David Kaye’s concern around the arrest and detention of digital activist Ola Bini’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152&quot;&gt;Article 19 have publicly&lt;/a&gt; echoed this concern and are closely monitoring the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Ola Bini was going to Japan for a martial arts training course, which he had advertised on twitter a week before. He was detained by the Ecuadorian police. In violation of due process, the police did not contact the Swedish authorities. This process is part of the standards of Ecuadorian law. After 15 hours of his initial detention, they made the contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini’s human rights have been violated repeatedly by the police, by the Ministry of the Interior, by the Attorney General’s office and by the judge in charge of the case. The agents who initially detained him did not have a valid warrant. He was denied access to his lawyers for 17 hours. He was not permitted to have a translator – even though his Spanish is rudimentary. He was not informed of the charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini was held at the airport for more than eight hours. In violation of Ecuadorian law, he was not transferred to the police facilities. The police then took him to his home, where they coerced him to allow access. Finally, he was taken to a facility abandoned by the judicial police, where he spent the night. By that time, he still did not have any access to legal advice or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning – on April 12 – Ola Bini was transferred to the Prosecutor&#39;s Office, where he remained for a further 12 hours before a hearing. For a total of 17 hours Ola Bini was not allowed legal advice or food. His lawyers report that they were harassed and threatened by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the hearing, the prosecutor offered no evidence against Ola Bini. Based on the Ecuadorian Penal Code, he was accused of one very serious crime – attacking the integrity of computer systems. Despite the lack of any evidence, the judge placed Ola Bini in pretrial detention for 90 days. There was no bail hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the process is politically motivated. Fabricated charges, with no evidence, have been brought against an innocent man. He has been caught in a dispute that does not concern him and with which he is not involved at all. There is not a single piece of evidence that incriminates him. Ola Bini sits in an Ecuadoran prison, denied bail, and with no guarantees of due process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a globally respected figure in the free software community, and a renowned activist for the right to privacy. In 2010, Computerworld magazine named him as Sweden&#39;s 6th best developer. He is a member of various European and international networks for free software and privacy, and he participates in projects of the highest level, some of them sponsored by the European Commission. Ola has never expressed any views that would in any way be a threat to the Ecuadorian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an advocate and an activist for the right to privacy, Ola has visited Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian Embassy in London several times. However, he does not work for Wikileaks, nor has he ever worked for them. Any allegation that he is conspiring against the Ecuadorian government and its computer systems is false and ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appeal to the Swedish Government to take firm, immediate action. So far, the Swedish Government&#39;s efforts have been limited to the presence of the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito.  While we are grateful that the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito involved himself we would ask you and the government to lift this to a political level, since it seems to be a political reason behind the arrest. We are sure that the misunderstanding about who Ola is and what he does could quickly be resolved. The Swedish Society and the Government of Sweden are recognized worldwide as active defenders and promoters of human rights and freedom of expression. His family, his friends, his colleagues, call on the Swedish government to intercede for Ola before the Ecuador authorities, demand respect for the law and for Ola’s human rights, and to facilitate his safe immediate return to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respectfully,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerned citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundahti Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Musician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Institute Professor (emeritus) MIT, Laureate Professor U. of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt;	/ Actress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25 co-founder, Professor of Economics – University of Athens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; 	/ Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1980, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt;	/ Writer and researcher on social implications of technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / French MP and President of the Parliamentary Group France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt;	/ Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1976, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Software Development Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Podemos, presidential candidate, Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Democracia en Red&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad Chancellor&#39;s&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor in the Department of Comparative Literature, University of California (Irvine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist/Activist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Coordinator of United Left Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Human Rights Lawyer, Co-founder of Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Miranda&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Whistleblower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Evengelical Front for a State of Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Former parliamentarian for the Civic Movement &amp;amp; Pirate Party in the Icelandic Parliament &amp;amp; chairman for IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; /	Rai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of the International Committee of the Brazilian Association of Jurists for Democracy - ABJD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; /	Political Innovation Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; /	Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; /	Veterans for Peace and former UN Diplomat, who resigned in 2003 in opposition to the US war on Iraq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; /	Author and co-editor, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; /	Novelist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; /	Attorney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; /	Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; /	City University of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; /	Danish programmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; /	Diem 25, and Co-Founder World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; /	Member of Coordinating Collective in DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; /	Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; /	Lawyer of Milagros de Sala and diverse causes of defense of human rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; /	General Secretary of the Spanish Communist Party, Human Rights Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; /	Sociologist, Activist, MEP candidate MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; /	European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; /	European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; /	Professor at UNIFESP University Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; /	Rai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; /	CTO Barcelona and DECODE project lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; /	Russell Tribunal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; /	Dominican friar and writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; /	University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; /	Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; /	First Deputy Mayor Barcelona City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; /	Professor - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; /	PhD Student/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; /	MP, Left Party Spokesperson on the Committee on International Relations of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; /	Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt; /	Sociologist - Universidade de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; /	General Secretary, National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; /	Director, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; /	European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; /	Founder of factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; /	National Direction of MST and of Brazil Popular Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; /	MST and Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; /	co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; /	Member of Regional Parliament of Thuringia (Mitglied des Landtages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; /	former CIA Counterterrorism Officer and former Senior Investigator, US Senate Foreign Relations Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling&lt;/strong&gt; / Dahl	CTO / fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; /	Spanish MP and General Secretary of the Parliamentary Group of Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; /	President of the Argentine League for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; /	Film Producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; /	Lawyer, CTEP leader and Patria Grande Front member. Coordinator of the dialogues of popular movements with Pope Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; /	DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; /	LRecipient of the UN Prize for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; /	Theologian,Philosopher and Member of the International Earth Charta Comission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; /	European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; /	Co-Founder European Alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; /	Vicepresident of the Party of the European Left (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; /	Patria Grande Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; /	Psychologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; /	President of La FEC, Foundation Europe of the Citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; /	Executive Director, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; /	CEPR, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; /	co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; /	Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; /	European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Legal Director, Software Freedom Law Centre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; /	Renewable Freedom Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; /	Chairman of The Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; /	Founder of ThoughtWorks, now retired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; /	CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; /	CEO at fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; /	Executive Director, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath    Founder&lt;/strong&gt; /, People’s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; /	Spanish MP and International Secretary of Podemos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; /	Principal Engineer, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; /	journalist and Decode advisory panel member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; /	Former minister for human rights and former coordinator of the National Truth Commision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; /	Muralist Painter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; /	Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / President Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; /	Executive Director, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William&lt;/strong&gt; / J. Barber II	Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; /	Publisher New Frame,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; /	Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; /	Popular education professor, photographer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; /	President of Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; /	Former Australian Senator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; /	MP, Vice Chair Left Parliamentary Group of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; /	Professor of History and Africana Studies, Williams College, Massachusetts USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; /	CAD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosopher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; /	comms director torproject, actor, writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; /	European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; /	Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; /	Historian and Teacher - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; /	Director, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; /	Professor - University, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; /	Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; /	Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / - Actor, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; /	Former Technical Director at NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; /	European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chandra&lt;/strong&gt; /	General Secretary Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yolanda Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; /	MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; /	UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; /	Artist, Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to the Prime Minister of Sweden</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/es/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/es/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Swedish national Ola Metodius Bini, a free software developer, was arrested in Quito (Ecuador). He has been living in the Republic of Ecuador for the past six years. Ola Bini is now serving a 90-day pretrial detention. He has not been afforded bail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Ola Bini has drawn worldwide concern. UN Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008&quot;&gt;David Kaye&lt;/a&gt; said that ‘nothing in this story connects Ola Bini to any crime’. Further, he said, ‘the govt of Ecuador must demonstrate more than that or this looks like an arbitrary detention’. The Organisation of American State’s Special Rapporteur for Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504&quot;&gt;Edison Lanza&lt;/a&gt;, added, ‘I share the Rapporteur David Kaye’s concern around the arrest and detention of digital activist Ola Bini’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152&quot;&gt;Article 19 have publicly&lt;/a&gt; echoed this concern and are closely monitoring the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Ola Bini was going to Japan for a martial arts training course, which he had advertised on twitter a week before. He was detained by the Ecuadorian police. In violation of due process, the police did not contact the Swedish authorities. This process is part of the standards of Ecuadorian law. After 15 hours of his initial detention, they made the contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini’s human rights have been violated repeatedly by the police, by the Ministry of the Interior, by the Attorney General’s office and by the judge in charge of the case. The agents who initially detained him did not have a valid warrant. He was denied access to his lawyers for 17 hours. He was not permitted to have a translator – even though his Spanish is rudimentary. He was not informed of the charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini was held at the airport for more than eight hours. In violation of Ecuadorian law, he was not transferred to the police facilities. The police then took him to his home, where they coerced him to allow access. Finally, he was taken to a facility abandoned by the judicial police, where he spent the night. By that time, he still did not have any access to legal advice or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning – on April 12 – Ola Bini was transferred to the Prosecutor&#39;s Office, where he remained for a further 12 hours before a hearing. For a total of 17 hours Ola Bini was not allowed legal advice or food. His lawyers report that they were harassed and threatened by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the hearing, the prosecutor offered no evidence against Ola Bini. Based on the Ecuadorian Penal Code, he was accused of one very serious crime – attacking the integrity of computer systems. Despite the lack of any evidence, the judge placed Ola Bini in pretrial detention for 90 days. There was no bail hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the process is politically motivated. Fabricated charges, with no evidence, have been brought against an innocent man. He has been caught in a dispute that does not concern him and with which he is not involved at all. There is not a single piece of evidence that incriminates him. Ola Bini sits in an Ecuadoran prison, denied bail, and with no guarantees of due process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a globally respected figure in the free software community, and a renowned activist for the right to privacy. In 2010, Computerworld magazine named him as Sweden&#39;s 6th best developer. He is a member of various European and international networks for free software and privacy, and he participates in projects of the highest level, some of them sponsored by the European Commission. Ola has never expressed any views that would in any way be a threat to the Ecuadorian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an advocate and an activist for the right to privacy, Ola has visited Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian Embassy in London several times. However, he does not work for Wikileaks, nor has he ever worked for them. Any allegation that he is conspiring against the Ecuadorian government and its computer systems is false and ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appeal to the Swedish Government to take firm, immediate action. So far, the Swedish Government&#39;s efforts have been limited to the presence of the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito.  While we are grateful that the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito involved himself we would ask you and the government to lift this to a political level, since it seems to be a political reason behind the arrest. We are sure that the misunderstanding about who Ola is and what he does could quickly be resolved. The Swedish Society and the Government of Sweden are recognized worldwide as active defenders and promoters of human rights and freedom of expression. His family, his friends, his colleagues, call on the Swedish government to intercede for Ola before the Ecuador authorities, demand respect for the law and for Ola’s human rights, and to facilitate his safe immediate return to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respectfully,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerned citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt; / Actress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Musician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25 co-founder, Professor of Economics – University of Athens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundhati Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Glover&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Institute Professor (emeritus) MIT, Laureate Professor U. of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1980, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt; / writer and researcher on social implications of technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosopher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / French MP and President of the Parliamentary Group France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Podemos, presidential candidate, Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1976, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Software Development Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Director - Democracia en Red -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; / Lawyer of Milagros de Sala and diverse causes of defense of human rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; / President of the Argentine League for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; / CTEP leader and Patria Grande Front member. Coordinator of the dialogues of popular movements with Pope Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; / Patria Grande Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; / President of La FEC, Foundation Europe of the Citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Australian Senator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; / Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25, and Co-Founder World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; / Political Innovation Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Evengelical Front for a State of Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of the International Committee of the Brazilian Association of Jurists for Democracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor at UNIFESP University Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; / Dominican friar and writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist - Universidade de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; / National Direction of MST and of Brazil Popular Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; / MST and Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; / Theologian, Philosopher and Member of the International Earth Charta Comission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Psychologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; / Former minister for human rights and former coordinator of the National Truth Commision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; / Historian and Teacher - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - University, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; / Author and co-editor, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; / Danish programmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; / Muralist Painter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; / Popular education professor, photographer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; / Technologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; / University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; / Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Whistleblower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; / Russell Tribunal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Miranda&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; / Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Left Party Spokesperson on the Committee on International Relations of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; / Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Regional Parliament of Thuringia (Mitglied des Landtages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; / Renewable Freedom Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Vice Chair Left Parliamentary Group of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; / Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytri Kleiner&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; / Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Coordinating Collective in DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist, Activist, MEP candidate MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Former parliamentarian for the Civic Movement &amp;amp; Pirate Party in the Icelandic Parliament &amp;amp; chairman for IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; / Chairman of The Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder, People’s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / President Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chandra&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO Barcelona and DECODE project lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; / Co-Founder European Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; / Laureate UN Human Rights Award 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; / PhD Student/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary, National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher - New Frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; / President of Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; / UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Coordinator of United Left Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Human Rights Lawyer, Co-founder of Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary of the Spanish Communist Party, Human Rights Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; / First Deputy Mayor Barcelona City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Secretary of the Parliamentary Group of Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; / Vice President of the Party of the European Left (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and International Secretary of Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yolanda Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; / MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling Dahl&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO / fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / CEO at fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Amroussia&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamma Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / GS (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heikel Belkacem&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jilani Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist and Decode advisory panel member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad&lt;/strong&gt; / Chancellor&#39;s Professor in the Department of Comparative Literature, University of California (Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist/Activist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Veterans for Peace and former UN Diplomat, who resigned in 2003 in opposition to the US war on Iraq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; / Novelist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; / Attorney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; / City University of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; / former CIA Counterterrorism Officer and former Senior Investigator, US Senate Foreign Relations Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; / Film Producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; / CEPR, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Legal Director, Software Freedom Law Centre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of ThoughtWorks, now retired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; / Principal Engineer, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William J. Barber II&lt;/strong&gt; / Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor of History and Africana Studies, Williams College, Massachusetts USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; / Communications Director - torproject. Actor, Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; / Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Technical Director at NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lettre au Premier ministre suédois</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/fr/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/fr/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monsieur le Premier Ministre Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le 11 avril, le citoyen suédois Ola Metodius Bini, développeur de logiciels libres, a été arrêté à Quito (Équateur). Il vit en Équateur depuis six ans. Ola Bini purge actuellement une peine de détention préventive de 90 jours. Il n&#39;a pas été libéré sous caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le cas d&#39;Ola Bini a suscité l&#39;inquiétude dans le monde entier. Le Rapporteur spécial des Nations Unies pour la liberté d&#39;expression, [David Kaye] (https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008) a déclaré que «rien dans cette histoire ne relie Ola Bini à un crime». En outre, at-il déclaré, &amp;quot;le gouvernement de l&#39;Équateur doit donner plus de preuves ou cela ressemble à une détention arbitraire&amp;quot;. Le rapporteur spécial de l&#39;Organisation des États américains pour la liberté d&#39;expression, [Edison Lanza] (https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504), a ajouté: &amp;quot;Je partage l&#39;inquiétude du rapporteur David Kaye concernant l&#39;arrestation et la détention de l&#39;activiste du numérique Ola Bini&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Amnesty International] (https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224) et [Article 19 ont publiquement] (https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152) fait l&#39;écho de cette préoccupation et suivent l&#39;affaire de près.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le 11 avril, Ola Bini se rendait au Japon pour suivre un cours d&#39;entraînement aux arts martiaux, qu&#39;il avait annoncée sur Twitter une semaine auparavant. Il a été arrêté par la police équatorienne. En violation des procédures, la police n&#39;a pas contacté les autorités suédoises. Cette procédure fait partie des normes du droit équatorien. Après 15 heures de sa détention initiale, ils ont finalement pris contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les droits individuels d&#39;Ola Bini ont été violés à plusieurs reprises par la police, par le Ministère de l&#39;intérieur, par le bureau du Procureur général et par le juge chargé de l&#39;affaire. Les agents qui l&#39;ont initialement arrêté n&#39;avaient pas de metat valide. Il s&#39;est vu refuser l&#39;accès à ses avocats pendant 17 heures. Il n&#39;a pas été autorisé à faire appel à un traducteur, même si son espagnol est rudimentaire. Il n&#39;a pas été informé des accusations portées contre lui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini a été retenu à l&#39;aéroport pendant plus de huit heures. En violation de la loi équatorienne, il n&#39;a pas été transféré aux locaux de police. La police l’a ensuite emmené chez lui, où ils l’ont forcé à faciliter l&#39;accès. Finalement, il a été emmené dans un établissement abetonné par la police judiciaire, où il a passé la nuit. À ce moment-là, il n&#39;avait toujours pas eu accès à des conseils juridiques ou assistance légale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le lendemain matin, le 12 avril, Ola Bini a été transféré au bureau du procureur, où il est resté 12 heures de plus avant son audience. Pendant un total de 17 heures, Ola Bini n&#39;a pas eu droit à des conseils juridiques ni à de la nourriture. Ses avocats rapportent qu&#39;ils ont été harcelés et menacés par la police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;À l&#39;audience, le procureur n&#39;a présenté aucune preuve contre Ola Bini. En vertu du code pénal équatorien, il a été accusé d&#39;un crime très grave: avoir porté atteinte à l&#39;intégrité de systèmes informatiques. Malgré le manque de preuves, le juge a placé Ola Bini en détention provisoire pendant 90 jours. Il n&#39;y a pas eu d&#39;audience de mise en liberté sous caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous croyons que le processus est motivé par des raisons politiques. Des charges fabriquées, sans preuve, ont été portées contre un homme innocent. Il s&#39;est retrouvé attrapé dans un conflit qui ne le concerne pas et dans lequel il n&#39;est pas impliqué du tout. Il n&#39;existe pas la moindre preuve qui puisse l&#39;incriminer. Ola Bini est détenu dans une prison équatorienne, refusé de liberté sous caution et sans garantie d&#39;une procédure régulière.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini est une figure mondialement respectée dans la communauté du logiciel libre et un activiste renommé du droit à la vie privée. En 2010, le magazine Computerworld l&#39;a nommé 6ème meilleur développeur de Suède. Il est membre de divers réseaux européens et internationaux pour le logiciel libre et la vie privée, et participe à des projets du plus haut niveau, dont certains parrainés par la Commission européenne. Ola n&#39;a jamais exprimé d&#39;opinion qui constituerait une menace pour le gouvernement équatorien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En tant que défenseur et activiste du droit au respect de la vie privée, Ola a rendu visite à Julian Assange à l’ambassade de l’Équateur à Londres à plusieurs reprises. Cependant, il ne travaille pas pour Wikileaks et n&#39;a jamais travaillé pour eux. Toute allégation selon laquelle il conspire contre le gouvernement équatorien et ses systèmes informatiques est fausse et ridicule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous appelons le gouvernement suédois à prendre des mesures fermes et immédiates. Jusqu&#39;à présent, les efforts du gouvernement suédois se sont limités à la présence du consul honoraire de Suède à Quito. Bien que nous soyons reconnaissants de la participation du consul honoraire suédois à Quito, nous vous demetons, à vous et au gouvernement, de porter cela à un niveau politique, car derrière cette arrestation semble avoir une raison politique. Nous sommes certains que le malentendu sur qui est Ola et ce qu&#39;il fait pourrait être rapidement résolu. La Société suédoise et le gouvernement suédois sont reconnus dans le monde entier comme des défenseurs actifs et des promoteurs des droits de l&#39;homme et de la liberté d&#39;expression. Sa famille, ses amis, ses collègues appellent le gouvernement suédois à intercéder pour Ola auprès des autorités équatoriennes, à exiger le respect de la loi et des droits de l&#39;homme d&#39;Ola et à faciliter son retour immédiat et sûr en Suède.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respectueusement,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les citoyens concernés&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt; / Comédienne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artiste, Musicien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / co-fondateur de DiEM25, Professeur d&#39;économie – Université d&#39;Athènes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundahti Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Auteur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Glover&lt;/strong&gt; / Comédien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Auteur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Professeur émérite au MIT, Professeur Lauréat Université d&#39;Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; / Lauréat du prix Nobel de la paix en 1980, Argentine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt; / écrivain et chercheur sur les implications sociales de la technologie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosophe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / Député français et président du groupe parlementaire France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / Secrétaire général de Podemos, candidat à la présidentielle, Espagne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt; / Lauréat du prix Nobel de la paix 1976, Royaume-Uni&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Auteur, Etats Unis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Auteur de développement de logiciels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Directeur - Democracia en Red -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; / Avocat de Milagros de Sala et diverses causes de défense des droits de l&#39;homme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; / Professeur - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; / Président de la Ligue argentine des droits de l&#39;homme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; / Chef de la CTEP et membre du front Patria Grande. Coordinateur du dialogue des mouvements populaires avec le Pape Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; / Front Patria Grete&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; / Présidente de la FEC, Fondation Europe des Citoyens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; / Ancien sénateur australien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; / Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25, et co-fondateur du World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; / Innovation politique Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / Comédien, Directeur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Front Evangélique pour un Etat des Droits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Membre du Comité international de l&#39;Association brésilienne des juristes pour la démocratie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journaliste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Professeur à l&#39;UNIFESP Université du Brésil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; / Frèere dominicain et écrivain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernetes&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologue - Université de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; / Direction Nationale du MST et du Front Populaire du Brésil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; / MST et Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; / Théologien, philosophe et membre de la comission International Earth Charta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Psychologue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; / Ancien ministre des droits de l&#39;homme et ancien coordinateur de la Commission National Truth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journaliste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; / Historien et enseignant - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; / Professeur - Université, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; / Auteur et co-éditeur, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Directeur, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; / Directeur exécutif, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; / Programmeur danois&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; / Peintre muraliste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; / Professeur d&#39;éducation populaire, photographe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; / Technologue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; / University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; / Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Lanceur d&#39;alerte, Dénonciateur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; / Tribunal Russell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Mireta&lt;/strong&gt; / Députée du Parlement européen, Groupe des Verts / Alliance libre européenne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Directrice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; / Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; / Députée, porte-parole du parti de gauche à la Commission des Relations Internationales du Bundestag allemand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; / Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Membre du Parlement régional de Thuringe (Mitglied des Lettages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; / Fondation Renewable Freedom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; / Député, vice-président du groupe parlementaire de gauche du Bundestag allemand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; / Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytri Kleiner&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; / Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; / Membre du collectif de coordination à DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologue, activiste, candidat eurodéputé MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; / Directeur exécutif, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Ancien parlementaire du Mouvement Civique et du Parti Pirate au parlement islandique et président de l&#39;IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; / Président du Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, Inde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath&lt;/strong&gt; / Fondateur, People&#39;s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / Président Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; / Directeur, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chetra&lt;/strong&gt; / Secrétaire général du mouvement du logiciel libre en Inde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; / Députée au Parlement (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; / Député au Parlement (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; / Auteur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; / Auteur, Directeur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO Barcelona et chef de projet pour DECODE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; / Co-Fondateur European Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; / Lauréat du Prix des droits de l&#39;homme des Nations Unies 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; / Doctorant/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; / Directeur Exécutif, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; / Secrétaire général du Syndicat national des métallurgistes d&#39;Afrique du Sud (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; / Editeur - New Frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; / Président du Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; / UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Député espagnol et coordinateur général du Parti de la Gauche Unie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Avocat des droits de l&#39;homme, co-fondateur de  Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; / Secrétaire général du Parti Communiste Espagnol, avocat des droits de l&#39;homme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; / Député du Parlement européen, Groupe des Verts / Alliance libre européenne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; / Parlement européen, Groupe confédéral de la Gauche Unitaire Européenne - Gauche Verte nordique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; / Premier adjoint au maire de Barcelone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; / Parlement européen, Groupe confédéral de la Gauche Unitaire Européenne - Gauche Verte nordique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; / Député espagnol et secrétaire général du groupe parlementaire du Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; / Parlement européen, Groupe confédéral de la Gauche Unitaire Européenne - Gauche Verte nordique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; / Vice-président du Parti de la gauche européenne (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; / Parlement européen, Groupe confédéral de la Gauche Unitaire Européenne - Gauche Verte nordique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; / Député espagnol et secrétaire international de Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; / Parlement européen, Groupe confédéral de la Gauche Unitaire Européenne - Gauche Verte nordique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Parlement européen, Groupe confédéral de la Gauche Unitaire Européenne - Gauche Verte nordique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoleta Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; / MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / Fondateur de factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling Dahl&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO de fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / CEO de fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; / Artiste, Suisse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Amroussia&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Front populaire) Tunisie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamma Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / GS (Front populaire) Tunisie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heikel Belkacem&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Front populaire) Tunisie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jilani Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Front populaire) Tunisie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; / Journaliste et Membre du panel consultatif pour DECODE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad&lt;/strong&gt; / Chancellor&#39;s Professor au département de littérature comparée de l&#39;Université de Californie (Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artiste/Activiste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Éditeur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Veterans for Peace et ancien diplomate des Nations Unies, qui a démissionné en 2003 pour s&#39;opposer à la guerre américaine en Irak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; / Romancière&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; / Avocat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; / City Université of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; / co-fondatrice CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; / ancien Officier du Contre-terrorisme de la CIA et ancien Chercheur Senior au Comité des Relations Extérieures du Sénat Américain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; / Producteur de films&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; / CEPR, Etats Unis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; / co-fondatrice CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Directrice juridique, Software Freedom Law Center&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Fondateur de ThoughtWorks, maintenant à la retraite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; / Ingénieur principal, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William J. Barber II&lt;/strong&gt; / Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, Etats Unis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Professeur d&#39;histoire et d&#39;études africaines, Williams College, Massachusetts, Etats Unis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; / Directeur des communications - torproject. Comédienne, Écrivaine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; / Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; / Ancien directeur technique à l&#39;Agence de Sécurité Nationale (NSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliations are listed for identification purposes&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lettera al Primo Ministro di Svezia</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/it/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/it/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Caro Primo Ministro Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&#39;11 aprile, il cittadino svedese Ola Metodius Bini, uno sviluppatore di software libero, è stato arrestato in Quito (Ecuador). Egli ha vissuto nella Repubblica dell&#39;Ecuador negli ultimi sei anni. Ola Bini sta ora scontando una detenzione preventiva di 90 giorni. Non gli è stata concessa la cauzione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il caso di Ola Bini ha destato preoccupazione a livello mondiale. Il relatore speciale delle Nazioni Unite sulla libertà di espressione, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008&quot;&gt;David Kaye&lt;/a&gt; ha affermato che &amp;quot;nulla in questa storia collega Ola Bini ad alcun crimine&amp;quot;. Inoltre, ha detto, &amp;quot;il governo dell&#39;Ecuador deve dimostrare più di questo altrimenti questa sembra una detenzione arbitraria&amp;quot;. L&#39;organizzazione del relatore speciale per la libertà di espressione dello Stato americano, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504&quot;&gt;Edison Lanza&lt;/a&gt;, ha aggiunto: &amp;quot;Condivido la preoccupazione del relatore David Kaye in merito all&#39;arresto e alla detenzione dell&#39;attivista digitale Ola Bini&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; e &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152&quot;&gt;Articolo 19 hanno pubblicamente&lt;/a&gt; ripetuto questa preoccupazione e stanno monitorando da vicino il caso.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&#39;11 aprile Ola Bini stava andando in Giappone per un corso di arti marziali, divulgandolo su twitter una settimana prima. È stato detenuto dalla polizia ecuadoriana. In violazione di giusto processo, la polizia non ha contattato le autorità svedesi. Questo processo dovrebbe essere parte degli standard della legge ecuadoriana. Dopo 15 ore dalla sua detenzione iniziale, hanno eseguito la notifica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I diritti umani di Ola Bini sono stati violati ripetutamente dalla polizia, dal Ministero dell&#39;Interno, dall&#39;ufficio del Procuratore Generale e dal giudice responsabile del caso. Gli agenti che inizialmente lo hanno detenuto non avevano un mandato valido. Gli è stato negato l&#39;accesso ai suoi avvocati per 17 ore. Non gli è stato permesso di avere un traduttore, anche se il suo spagnolo è rudimentale. Non è stato informato delle accuse contro di lui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini è stato trattenuto all&#39;aeroporto per più di otto ore. In violazione della legge ecuadoriana, non è stato trasferito alle strutture di polizia. La polizia poi lo ha portato alla sua dimora, dove lo haano costretto a permettergli l&#39;accesso. Alla fine, è stato portato in una struttura abbandonata dalla polizia giudiziaria, dove ha trascorso la notte. Fino a quel momento, non gli è stato fornito nessun accesso ad assistenza o consulenza legale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il mattino seguente - il 12 aprile - Ola Bini è stato trasferito all&#39;Ufficio del Procuratore, dove è rimasto per altre 12 ore prima di un&#39;udienza. Per un totale di 17 ore a Ola Bini non è stato consentito l&#39;accesso a parere legale o cibo. I suoi avvocati riferiscono di essere stati molestati e minacciati dalla polizia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All&#39;udienza, il pubblico ministero non ha offerto alcuna prova contro Ola Bini. In base al Codice Penale ecuadoriano, è stato accusato di un crimine molto grave - attacco all&#39;integrità di sistemi informatici. Nonostante la mancanza di prove, il giudice ha posto Ola Bini in detenzione preventiva per 90 giorni. Non c&#39;è  stata udienza per la cauzione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crediamo che il processo sia politicamente motivato. Accuse fabbricate, senza prove, sono state portate contro un innocente. È stato intrappolato in una disputa che non lo riguarda e nel quale non è affatto coinvolto. Non c&#39;è una singola prova che lo incrimina. Ola Bini è trattenuto in una prigione ecuadoriana, ha negata la sua libertà su cauzione e non ha garanzie di giusto processo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini è una figura rispettata a livello mondiale nella comunità del software libero e un rinomato attivista per il diritto alla privacy. Nel 2010, la rivista Computerworld lo ha nominato il 6° miglior sviluppatore della Svezia. È membro di varie reti europee e internazionali per software libero e privacy, e partecipa a progetti di altissimo livello, alcuni dei quali sponsorizzati dalla Commissione Europea. Ola non ha mai espresso alcuna opinione che sarebbe in alcun modo una minaccia per il governo ecuadoriano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come sostenitore e attivista per il diritto alla privacy, Ola ha visitato più volte Julian Assange presso l&#39;ambasciata ecuadoriana a Londra. Tuttavia, non lavora per Wikileaks, né ha mai lavorato per loro. Ogni accusa di cospirazione contro il governo ecuadoriano e i suoi sistemi informatici è falsa e ridicola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facciamo appello al governo svedese affinché intraprenda un&#39;azione ferma e immediata. Finora, gli sforzi del governo svedese si sono limitati alla presenza del Console Onorario svedese a Quito. Mentre siamo grati che il Console Onorario svedese di Quito si sia impegnato, chiederemo a te e al governo di sollevare queto caso a livello politico, poiché sembra esserci una ragione politica dietro l&#39;arresto. Siamo sicuri che l&#39;equivoco su chi sia Ola e di cosa si occupa possa essere risolto rapidamente. La società svedese e il governo svedese sono riconosciuti in tutto il mondo come promotori e difensori attivi dei diritti umani e della libertà di espressione. La sua famiglia, i suoi amici, i suoi colleghi, invitiamo il governo svedese a intercedere per Ola davanti presso le autorità ecuadoriane, chiediamo rispetto per la legge e per i diritti umani di Ola, e di facilitare il suo immediato ritorno in sicurezza in Svezia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rispettosamente,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cittadini preoccupati&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt; / Actress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Musician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25 co-founder, Professor of Economics – University of Athens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundahti Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Glover&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Institute Professor (emeritus) MIT, Laureate Professor U. of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1980, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt; / writer and researcher on social implications of technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosopher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / French MP and President of the Parliamentary Group France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Podemos, presidential candidate, Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1976, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Software Development Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Director - Democracia en Red -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; / Lawyer of Milagros de Sala and diverse causes of defense of human rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; / President of the Argentine League for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; / CTEP leader and Patria Grande Front member. Coordinator of the dialogues of popular movements with Pope Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; / Patria Grande Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; / President of La FEC, Foundation Europe of the Citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Australian Senator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; / Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25, and Co-Founder World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; / Political Innovation Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Evengelical Front for a State of Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of the International Committee of the Brazilian Association of Jurists for Democracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor at UNIFESP University Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; / Dominican friar and writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist - Universidade de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; / National Direction of MST and of Brazil Popular Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; / MST and Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; / Theologian, Philosopher and Member of the International Earth Charta Comission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Psychologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; / Former minister for human rights and former coordinator of the National Truth Commision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; / Historian and Teacher - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - University, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; / Author and co-editor, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; / Danish programmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; / Muralist Painter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; / Popular education professor, photographer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; / Technologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; / University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; / Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Whistleblower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; / Russell Tribunal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Miranda&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; / Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Left Party Spokesperson on the Committee on International Relations of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; / Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Regional Parliament of Thuringia (Mitglied des Landtages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; / Renewable Freedom Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Vice Chair Left Parliamentary Group of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; / Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytri Kleiner&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; / Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Coordinating Collective in DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist, Activist, MEP candidate MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Former parliamentarian for the Civic Movement &amp;amp; Pirate Party in the Icelandic Parliament &amp;amp; chairman for IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; / Chairman of The Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder, People’s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / President Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chandra&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO Barcelona and DECODE project lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; / Co-Founder European Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; / Laureate UN Human Rights Award 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; / PhD Student/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary, National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher - New Frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; / President of Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; / UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Coordinator of United Left Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Human Rights Lawyer, Co-founder of Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary of the Spanish Communist Party, Human Rights Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; / First Deputy Mayor Barcelona City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Secretary of the Parliamentary Group of Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; / Vice President of the Party of the European Left (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and International Secretary of Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yolanda Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; / MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling Dahl&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO / fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / CEO at fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Amroussia&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamma Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / GS (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heikel Belkacem&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jilani Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist and Decode advisory panel member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad&lt;/strong&gt; / Chancellor&#39;s Professor in the Department of Comparative Literature, University of California (Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist/Activist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Veterans for Peace and former UN Diplomat, who resigned in 2003 in opposition to the US war on Iraq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; / Novelist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; / Attorney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; / City University of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; / former CIA Counterterrorism Officer and former Senior Investigator, US Senate Foreign Relations Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; / Film Producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; / CEPR, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Legal Director, Software Freedom Law Centre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of ThoughtWorks, now retired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; / Principal Engineer, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William J. Barber II&lt;/strong&gt; / Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor of History and Africana Studies, Williams College, Massachusetts USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; / Communications Director - torproject. Actor, Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; / Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Technical Director at NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliations are listed for identification purposes&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to the Prime Minister of Sweden</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/pt/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/pt/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Swedish national Ola Metodius Bini, a free software developer, was arrested in Quito (Ecuador). He has been living in the Republic of Ecuador for the past six years. Ola Bini is now serving a 90-day pretrial detention. He has not been afforded bail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Ola Bini has drawn worldwide concern. UN Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008&quot;&gt;David Kaye&lt;/a&gt; said that ‘nothing in this story connects Ola Bini to any crime’. Further, he said, ‘the govt of Ecuador must demonstrate more than that or this looks like an arbitrary detention’. The Organisation of American State’s Special Rapporteur for Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504&quot;&gt;Edison Lanza&lt;/a&gt;, added, ‘I share the Rapporteur David Kaye’s concern around the arrest and detention of digital activist Ola Bini’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152&quot;&gt;Article 19 have publicly&lt;/a&gt; echoed this concern and are closely monitoring the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Ola Bini was going to Japan for a martial arts training course, which he had advertised on twitter a week before. He was detained by the Ecuadorian police. In violation of due process, the police did not contact the Swedish authorities. This process is part of the standards of Ecuadorian law. After 15 hours of his initial detention, they made the contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini’s human rights have been violated repeatedly by the police, by the Ministry of the Interior, by the Attorney General’s office and by the judge in charge of the case. The agents who initially detained him did not have a valid warrant. He was denied access to his lawyers for 17 hours. He was not permitted to have a translator – even though his Spanish is rudimentary. He was not informed of the charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini was held at the airport for more than eight hours. In violation of Ecuadorian law, he was not transferred to the police facilities. The police then took him to his home, where they coerced him to allow access. Finally, he was taken to a facility abandoned by the judicial police, where he spent the night. By that time, he still did not have any access to legal advice or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning – on April 12 – Ola Bini was transferred to the Prosecutor&#39;s Office, where he remained for a further 12 hours before a hearing. For a total of 17 hours Ola Bini was not allowed legal advice or food. His lawyers report that they were harassed and threatened by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the hearing, the prosecutor offered no evidence against Ola Bini. Based on the Ecuadorian Penal Code, he was accused of one very serious crime – attacking the integrity of computer systems. Despite the lack of any evidence, the judge placed Ola Bini in pretrial detention for 90 days. There was no bail hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the process is politically motivated. Fabricated charges, with no evidence, have been brought against an innocent man. He has been caught in a dispute that does not concern him and with which he is not involved at all. There is not a single piece of evidence that incriminates him. Ola Bini sits in an Ecuadoran prison, denied bail, and with no guarantees of due process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a globally respected figure in the free software community, and a renowned activist for the right to privacy. In 2010, Computerworld magazine named him as Sweden&#39;s 6th best developer. He is a member of various European and international networks for free software and privacy, and he participates in projects of the highest level, some of them sponsored by the European Commission. Ola has never expressed any views that would in any way be a threat to the Ecuadorian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an advocate and an activist for the right to privacy, Ola has visited Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian Embassy in London several times. However, he does not work for Wikileaks, nor has he ever worked for them. Any allegation that he is conspiring against the Ecuadorian government and its computer systems is false and ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appeal to the Swedish Government to take firm, immediate action. So far, the Swedish Government&#39;s efforts have been limited to the presence of the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito.  While we are grateful that the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito involved himself we would ask you and the government to lift this to a political level, since it seems to be a political reason behind the arrest. We are sure that the misunderstanding about who Ola is and what he does could quickly be resolved. The Swedish Society and the Government of Sweden are recognized worldwide as active defenders and promoters of human rights and freedom of expression. His family, his friends, his colleagues, call on the Swedish government to intercede for Ola before the Ecuador authorities, demand respect for the law and for Ola’s human rights, and to facilitate his safe immediate return to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respectfully,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerned citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt; / Actress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Musician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25 co-founder, Professor of Economics – University of Athens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundahti Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Glover&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Institute Professor (emeritus) MIT, Laureate Professor U. of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1980, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt; / writer and researcher on social implications of technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosopher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / French MP and President of the Parliamentary Group France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Podemos, presidential candidate, Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1976, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Software Development Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Director - Democracia en Red -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; / Lawyer of Milagros de Sala and diverse causes of defense of human rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; / President of the Argentine League for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; / CTEP leader and Patria Grande Front member. Coordinator of the dialogues of popular movements with Pope Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; / Patria Grande Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; / President of La FEC, Foundation Europe of the Citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Australian Senator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; / Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25, and Co-Founder World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; / Political Innovation Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Evengelical Front for a State of Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of the International Committee of the Brazilian Association of Jurists for Democracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor at UNIFESP University Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; / Dominican friar and writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist - Universidade de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; / National Direction of MST and of Brazil Popular Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; / MST and Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; / Theologian, Philosopher and Member of the International Earth Charta Comission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Psychologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; / Former minister for human rights and former coordinator of the National Truth Commision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; / Historian and Teacher - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - University, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; / Author and co-editor, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; / Danish programmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; / Muralist Painter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; / Popular education professor, photographer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; / Technologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; / University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; / Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Whistleblower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; / Russell Tribunal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Miranda&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; / Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Left Party Spokesperson on the Committee on International Relations of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; / Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Regional Parliament of Thuringia (Mitglied des Landtages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; / Renewable Freedom Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Vice Chair Left Parliamentary Group of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; / Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytri Kleiner&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; / Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Coordinating Collective in DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist, Activist, MEP candidate MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Former parliamentarian for the Civic Movement &amp;amp; Pirate Party in the Icelandic Parliament &amp;amp; chairman for IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; / Chairman of The Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder, People’s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / President Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chandra&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO Barcelona and DECODE project lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; / Co-Founder European Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; / Laureate UN Human Rights Award 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; / PhD Student/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary, National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher - New Frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; / President of Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; / UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Coordinator of United Left Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Human Rights Lawyer, Co-founder of Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary of the Spanish Communist Party, Human Rights Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; / First Deputy Mayor Barcelona City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Secretary of the Parliamentary Group of Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; / Vice President of the Party of the European Left (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and International Secretary of Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yolanda Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; / MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling Dahl&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO / fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / CEO at fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Amroussia&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamma Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / GS (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heikel Belkacem&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jilani Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist and Decode advisory panel member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad&lt;/strong&gt; / Chancellor&#39;s Professor in the Department of Comparative Literature, University of California (Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist/Activist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Veterans for Peace and former UN Diplomat, who resigned in 2003 in opposition to the US war on Iraq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; / Novelist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; / Attorney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; / City University of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; / former CIA Counterterrorism Officer and former Senior Investigator, US Senate Foreign Relations Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; / Film Producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; / CEPR, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Legal Director, Software Freedom Law Centre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of ThoughtWorks, now retired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; / Principal Engineer, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William J. Barber II&lt;/strong&gt; / Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor of History and Africana Studies, Williams College, Massachusetts USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; / Communications Director - torproject. Actor, Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; / Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Technical Director at NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliations are listed for identification purposes&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to the Prime Minister of Sweden</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/sv/letter-swedish-pm/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/sv/letter-swedish-pm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister Stefan Löfven,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Swedish national Ola Metodius Bini, a free software developer, was arrested in Quito (Ecuador). He has been living in the Republic of Ecuador for the past six years. Ola Bini is now serving a 90-day pretrial detention. He has not been afforded bail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Ola Bini has drawn worldwide concern. UN Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidakaye/status/1117489081397547008&quot;&gt;David Kaye&lt;/a&gt; said that ‘nothing in this story connects Ola Bini to any crime’. Further, he said, ‘the govt of Ecuador must demonstrate more than that or this looks like an arbitrary detention’. The Organisation of American State’s Special Rapporteur for Freedom of Expression, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdisonLanza/status/1117552044737429504&quot;&gt;Edison Lanza&lt;/a&gt;, added, ‘I share the Rapporteur David Kaye’s concern around the arrest and detention of digital activist Ola Bini’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikaGuevaraR/status/1117791352488628224&quot;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/article19org/status/1117789379802673152&quot;&gt;Article 19 have publicly&lt;/a&gt; echoed this concern and are closely monitoring the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 11, Ola Bini was going to Japan for a martial arts training course, which he had advertised on twitter a week before. He was detained by the Ecuadorian police. In violation of due process, the police did not contact the Swedish authorities. This process is part of the standards of Ecuadorian law. After 15 hours of his initial detention, they made the contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini’s human rights have been violated repeatedly by the police, by the Ministry of the Interior, by the Attorney General’s office and by the judge in charge of the case. The agents who initially detained him did not have a valid warrant. He was denied access to his lawyers for 17 hours. He was not permitted to have a translator – even though his Spanish is rudimentary. He was not informed of the charges against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini was held at the airport for more than eight hours. In violation of Ecuadorian law, he was not transferred to the police facilities. The police then took him to his home, where they coerced him to allow access. Finally, he was taken to a facility abandoned by the judicial police, where he spent the night. By that time, he still did not have any access to legal advice or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning – on April 12 – Ola Bini was transferred to the Prosecutor&#39;s Office, where he remained for a further 12 hours before a hearing. For a total of 17 hours Ola Bini was not allowed legal advice or food. His lawyers report that they were harassed and threatened by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the hearing, the prosecutor offered no evidence against Ola Bini. Based on the Ecuadorian Penal Code, he was accused of one very serious crime – attacking the integrity of computer systems. Despite the lack of any evidence, the judge placed Ola Bini in pretrial detention for 90 days. There was no bail hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the process is politically motivated. Fabricated charges, with no evidence, have been brought against an innocent man. He has been caught in a dispute that does not concern him and with which he is not involved at all. There is not a single piece of evidence that incriminates him. Ola Bini sits in an Ecuadoran prison, denied bail, and with no guarantees of due process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini is a globally respected figure in the free software community, and a renowned activist for the right to privacy. In 2010, Computerworld magazine named him as Sweden&#39;s 6th best developer. He is a member of various European and international networks for free software and privacy, and he participates in projects of the highest level, some of them sponsored by the European Commission. Ola has never expressed any views that would in any way be a threat to the Ecuadorian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an advocate and an activist for the right to privacy, Ola has visited Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian Embassy in London several times. However, he does not work for Wikileaks, nor has he ever worked for them. Any allegation that he is conspiring against the Ecuadorian government and its computer systems is false and ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appeal to the Swedish Government to take firm, immediate action. So far, the Swedish Government&#39;s efforts have been limited to the presence of the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito.  While we are grateful that the Swedish Honorary Consul in Quito involved himself we would ask you and the government to lift this to a political level, since it seems to be a political reason behind the arrest. We are sure that the misunderstanding about who Ola is and what he does could quickly be resolved. The Swedish Society and the Government of Sweden are recognized worldwide as active defenders and promoters of human rights and freedom of expression. His family, his friends, his colleagues, call on the Swedish government to intercede for Ola before the Ecuador authorities, demand respect for the law and for Ola’s human rights, and to facilitate his safe immediate return to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respectfully,
Concerned citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pamela Anderson&lt;/strong&gt; / Actress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Musician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yanis Varoufakis&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25 co-founder, Professor of Economics – University of Athens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arundahti Roy&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Glover&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Eggers&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/strong&gt; / Institute Professor (emeritus) MIT, Laureate Professor U. of Arizona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adolfo Perez Esquivel&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1980, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evgeny Morozov&lt;/strong&gt; / writer and researcher on social implications of technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Srecko Horvat&lt;/strong&gt; / Philosopher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Luc Mélenchon&lt;/strong&gt; / French MP and President of the Parliamentary Group France Insoumise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Iglesias&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Podemos, presidential candidate, Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairead Maguire&lt;/strong&gt; / Recipient Nobel Peace Prize 1976, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendela Vida&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/strong&gt; / Software Development Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agustín Frizzera&lt;/strong&gt; / Director - Democracia en Red -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eli Gomez Alcorta&lt;/strong&gt; / Lawyer of Milagros de Sala and diverse causes of defense of human rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gloria Verónica Sammartino&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - Universidad Buenos Aires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Shultman&lt;/strong&gt; / President of the Argentine League for Human Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juan Grabois&lt;/strong&gt; / CTEP leader and Patria Grande Front member. Coordinator of the dialogues of popular movements with Pope Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manuel Bertoldi&lt;/strong&gt; / Patria Grande Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marga Ferré&lt;/strong&gt; / President of La FEC, Foundation Europe of the Citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scott Ludlam&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Australian Senator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Norton&lt;/strong&gt; / Digital Rights Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davide Castro&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25, and Co-Founder World Solidarity Forum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Leon&lt;/strong&gt; / Political Innovation Asuntos del Sur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wagner Moura&lt;/strong&gt; / Actor, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariovaldo Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; / Evengelical Front for a State of Rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernardo Loureiro Jurema&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Proner&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of the International Committee of the Brazilian Association of Jurists for Democracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleonora de Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabio Luis Barbosa dos Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor at UNIFESP University Brazil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frei Betto&lt;/strong&gt; / Dominican friar and writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heloisa Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist - Universidade de São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Paulo Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt; / National Direction of MST and of Brazil Popular Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Pedro Stedile&lt;/strong&gt; / MST and Via Campesina Brasil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonardo Boff&lt;/strong&gt; / Theologian, Philosopher and Member of the International Earth Charta Comission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Antonio Santos&lt;/strong&gt; / Psychologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paulo Sergio Pinheiro&lt;/strong&gt; / Former minister for human rights and former coordinator of the National Truth Commision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rodolfo Lucena&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valerio Arcary&lt;/strong&gt; / Historian and Teacher - IFET São Paulo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgínia Fontes&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor - University, Rio de Janeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/strong&gt; / Author and co-editor, Boing Boing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Arteaga&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Díaz Cruz&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Extituto de Política Abierta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/strong&gt; / Danish programmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfredo Velazco&lt;/strong&gt; / Usuarios Digitales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Égüez&lt;/strong&gt; / Muralist Painter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubén Zavala&lt;/strong&gt; / Popular education professor, photographer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sofía Celi&lt;/strong&gt; / Technologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Danezis&lt;/strong&gt; / University College London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicklas Andersson&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perti Sumula&lt;/strong&gt; / Association - Friends of the MST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/strong&gt; / Whistleblower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank Barat&lt;/strong&gt; / Russell Tribunal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Miranda&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Richter&lt;/strong&gt; / Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geraldine de Bastion&lt;/strong&gt; / Konnektiv Kollektiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heike Hänsel&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Left Party Spokesperson on the Committee on International Relations of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Buecker&lt;/strong&gt; / Coop Anti-War Cafe Berlin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Scheringer-Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Regional Parliament of Thuringia (Mitglied des Landtages Thüringen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Wojcik&lt;/strong&gt; / DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moritz Bartl&lt;/strong&gt; / Renewable Freedom Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sevim Dagdelen&lt;/strong&gt; / MP, Vice Chair Left Parliamentary Group of the German Bundestag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Palmetshofer&lt;/strong&gt; / Open Knowledge Foundation Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytri Kleiner&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Adler&lt;/strong&gt; / Diem25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eirini Mitsiou&lt;/strong&gt; / Member of Coordinating Collective in DiEM25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik Edman&lt;/strong&gt; / Sociologist, Activist, MEP candidate MeRA25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renata Avila&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, Fundación Ciudadanía Inteligente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Jónsdóttir&lt;/strong&gt; / Former parliamentarian for the Civic Movement &amp;amp; Pirate Party in the Icelandic Parliament &amp;amp; chairman for IMMI (International Modern Media Institute).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Ram&lt;/strong&gt; / Chairman of The Hindu Publishing Group, Chennai, India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P. Sainath&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder, People’s Archive of Rural India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prabir Purkayastha&lt;/strong&gt; / President Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Prashad&lt;/strong&gt; / Director, Tricontinental: Institute for Social Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y Kiran Chandra&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary Free Software Movement of India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clare Daly&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mick Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; / Deputy to the Dáil (MP), Independents 4 Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlo Freccero&lt;/strong&gt; / Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felice Cappa&lt;/strong&gt; / Author, Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesca Bria&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO Barcelona and DECODE project lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenzo Marsili&lt;/strong&gt; / Co-Founder European Alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khadija Ryadi&lt;/strong&gt; / Laureate UN Human Rights Award 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gustavo Banegas&lt;/strong&gt; / PhD Student/Technische Universiteit Eindhoven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maricarmen Sequera&lt;/strong&gt; / Executive Director, TEDIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irvin Jim&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary, National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Richard Pithouse&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher - New Frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&#39;bu Zikode&lt;/strong&gt; / President of Abahlali BaseMjondolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zackie Achmat&lt;/strong&gt; / UniteBehind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Garzón&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Coordinator of United Left Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almudena Bernabéu&lt;/strong&gt; / Human Rights Lawyer, Co-founder of Guernica 37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrique Santiago&lt;/strong&gt; / General Secretary of the Spanish Communist Party, Human Rights Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ernest Urtasun&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Group of the Greens/European Free Alliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estefanía Torres Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerardo Pisarello&lt;/strong&gt; / First Deputy Mayor Barcelona City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier Couso Permuy&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José María Guijarro&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and General Secretary of the Parliamentary Group of Unidas Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lola Sánchez Caldentey&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maite Mola&lt;/strong&gt; / Vice President of the Party of the European Left (PEL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urban&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pablo Bustinduy&lt;/strong&gt; / Spanish MP and International Secretary of Podemos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania González Peñas&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xabier Benito Ziluaga&lt;/strong&gt; / European Parliament MP, Confederal Group of the European United Left - Nordic Green Left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yolanda Cvitak&lt;/strong&gt; / MundoJusto&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of factor10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon-Erling Dahl&lt;/strong&gt; / CTO / fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas Nilsson&lt;/strong&gt; / CEO at fooheads AB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zimoun&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist, Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Amroussia&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamma Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / GS (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heikel Belkacem&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jilani Hammami&lt;/strong&gt; / MP (Popular Front) Tunisia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Mason&lt;/strong&gt; / Journalist and Decode advisory panel member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aijaz Ahmad&lt;/strong&gt; / Chancellor&#39;s Professor in the Department of Comparative Literature, University of California (Irvine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Leger&lt;/strong&gt; / Artist/Activist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthony Arnove&lt;/strong&gt; / Publisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colonel Ann Wright&lt;/strong&gt; / Veterans for Peace and former UN Diplomat, who resigned in 2003 in opposition to the US war on Iraq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina García&lt;/strong&gt; / Novelist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Goodwin&lt;/strong&gt; / Attorney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; / City University of New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jodie Evans&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Kiriakou&lt;/strong&gt; / former CIA Counterterrorism Officer and former Senior Investigator, US Senate Foreign Relations Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joslyn Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; / Film Producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weisbrot&lt;/strong&gt; / CEPR, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medea Benjamin&lt;/strong&gt; / co-founder CODEPINK; Women for Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mishi Choudhary&lt;/strong&gt; / Legal Director, Software Freedom Law Centre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville Roy Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Founder of ThoughtWorks, now retired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Linskey&lt;/strong&gt; / Principal Engineer, Cisco Systems Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverend Dr. William J. Barber II&lt;/strong&gt; / Repairers of the Breach and Poor Peoples Campaign, USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shanti Marie Singham&lt;/strong&gt; / Professor of History and Africana Studies, Williams College, Massachusetts USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Whited&lt;/strong&gt; / Communications Director - torproject. Actor, Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivien Lesnik Weisman&lt;/strong&gt; / Latinovision Productions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William E. Binney&lt;/strong&gt; / Former Technical Director at NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Resende Haddad&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Pyenson&lt;/strong&gt; /&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliations are listed for identification purposes&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Please Tweet This!</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/en/tweet-this/"/>
    <updated>2019-05-02T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/en/tweet-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini remains in prison in Ecuador. Help spread the word by tweeting these messages.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Por favor Twittea Esto!</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/es/tweet-this/"/>
    <updated>2019-05-02T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/es/tweet-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini sigue en detención en Ecuador. Ayúdanos a difundir la palabra twitteando estos mensajes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>S&#39;il te plaît, partage sur Twitter!</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/fr/tweet-this/"/>
    <updated>2019-05-02T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/fr/tweet-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini est toujours en prison en Equateur. Aidez à diffuser le message en tweetant ces messages.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Twitta questi messaggi per favore!</title>
    <link href="http://freeolabini.org/it/tweet-this/"/>
    <updated>2019-05-02T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://freeolabini.org/it/tweet-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ola Bini rimane detenuto in prigione in Ecuador. Aiuta a diffondere il messaggio twittando questi messaggi.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
